[birds chirping]
[鸟鸣声]
[banging in distance]
[远处敲击声]
[banging continues]
[敲击声持续]
[lock clicks]
[keys jingling]
[锁具咔嗒声]
[钥匙叮当声]
[Duane] Jade, I need you
to start on the bathrooms.
[杜安] 杰德，我需要你
开始打扫卫生间。
Joslyn, can you please
take out all the eggs, batter,
乔斯林，请你
把所有的鸡蛋、面糊、
patties and McMuffins
out of the freezer, okay?
肉饼和麦满分
从冰柜里拿出来，好吗？
I’ll help you
once I turn everything on.
我会帮你
等我启动所有设备后。
[sets down keys]
[放下钥匙]
[singsongy]
Good morning, team.
[哼唱腔]
早上好，各位。
[women scream]
[女性尖叫声]
[Jeffrey]
No, no, no.
[杰弗里]
不，不，不。
Don’t be scared.
别害怕。
You just do what I say,
no one gets hurt, okay?
你们只要按我说的做，
就不会有人受伤，明白吗？
[gasps]
No, no, look.
[倒吸一口气]
不，不，看好了。
Pointing it down.
枪口朝下。
Okay, now,
I’m gonna say a polite
好了，现在，
我会说一句礼貌
and cheerful "Good morning,"
and then you guys say it back.
又愉快的“早上好”，
然后你们跟着说一遍。
Good morning.
早上好。
No... Duane, after I say it.
不…杜安，要等我说完。
That’s how that works. Okay?
规矩是这样的。明白吗？
Now, good morning, team.
好了，早上好，各位。
[all]
Good morning.
[众人]
早上好。
Yes. Perfect.
对。完美。
I say what to do
and you guys just do it. Okay.
我说做什么
你们就照做。好了。
I want you to get
your coats back on.
我要你们
把外套重新穿上。
Duane, grab your coat.
杜安，穿上你的外套。
[Duane] Huh?
Grab your coat.
[杜安] 嗯？
穿上你的外套。
I don’t have one, sir.
我没有外套，先生。
You don’t have a coat?
How do you not have a coat?
你没有外套？
你怎么会没有外套？
I just forgot.
我只是忘了带。
[sighs]
[叹气]
Well, you’re just gonna
have to be a little cold today.
好吧，那你今天
只能稍微挨点冻了。
All right, let’s go.
好了，我们走吧。
After you. Ladies first.
您先请。女士优先。
Now, listen to me.
现在，听我说。
You guys aren’t
gonna die in here.
你们不会
死在这里的。
Soon as I’m out of here,
I’m gonna call the cops
等我离开这里，
我就会报警
and they’re gonna
let you guys out.
然后他们会
放你们出去的。
Probably get the day off.
说不定还能放一天假。
No, don’t, don’t.
不，别，别这样。
Do not look at me like that.
别那样看着我。
Duane, stop it.
杜安，住手。
’Cause this is your fault.
因为这都是你的错。
It’s cold.
好冷。
Are you serious?
你是认真的吗？
[sighs]
[叹气]
Dang it.
真该死。
I don’t know what kind of jerk
我真不知道是哪种混蛋
doesn’t bring his own coat
to work.
上班会不自己带外套
来。
Okay? Happy now?
好了吧？现在满意了？
[Duane]
My ears are cold.
[杜安]
我的耳朵好冷。
[Jeffrey]
<i>This is the part of the story</i>
[杰弗里]
<i>故事的这一部分</i>
<i>where I hope you’re wondering</i>
<i>我希望你会好奇</i>
<i>how a nice guy like me
ends up becoming a criminal.</i>
<i>像我这样的好人
最终怎么会沦为罪犯。</i>
[Scheimreif over speaker]
<i>Hello?</i>
[扬声器里的沙伊姆赖夫]
<i>喂？</i>
<i>This thing on?</i>
<i>这东西开着吗？</i>
<i>Hello?</i>
<i>喂？</i>
[Jeffrey]
Shit!
[杰弗里]
妈的！
[Scheimreif over speaker]
<i>Come on, Duane.</i>
[扬声器里的沙伊姆赖夫]
<i>拜托，杜安。</i>
Good morning.
Uh, welcome to McDonald’s.
早上好。
呃，欢迎来到麦当劳。
I’m gonna put you on
a brief hold.
我需要让你
稍等片刻。
[Scheimreif over speaker]
<i>What the hell, Duane?</i>
[扬声器里的沙伊姆赖夫]
<i>搞什么鬼，杜安？</i>
[Jeffrey]
<i>I can’t blame my parents.</i>
[杰弗里]
<i>我不能怪我的父母。</i>
<i>I had a good childhood.</i>
<i>我有一个美好的童年。</i>
<i>I was just never good
at school or behaving.</i>
<i>我只是从来都不擅长
学习或循规蹈矩。</i>
<i>But I was good
at certain things</i>
<i>但我在某些方面
确实很在行</i>
<i>that were really valuable
to the military.</i>
<i>这些技能对军队来说</i>
<i>确实很有价值。</i>
<i>But after my discharge,</i>
<i>但退伍之后，</i>
<i>I didn’t know where I fit
or what to do</i>
<i>我不知道自己该何去何从，</i>
<i>也不知道该做什么，</i>
<i>or how to give my kids
the things that other kids had.</i>
<i>更不知道如何给我的孩子们</i>
<i>提供其他孩子拥有的东西。</i>
<i>So I made some bad choices
that took away
some other choices.</i>
<i>于是我做出了一些错误的选择，</i>
<i>这些选择剥夺了</i>
<i>我其他的可能性。</i>
<i>And those bad choices
all started two years ago</i>
<i>而这些错误的选择</i>
<i>都始于两年前</i>
<i>at my daughter’s
sixth birthday party.</i>
<i>在我女儿的</i>
<i>六岁生日派对上。</i>
[happy chatter]
[dog barking]
[欢乐的交谈声]
[狗叫声]
[Jeffrey] All right,
you got to make a big ol’ wish.
[杰弗里] 好了，
许个大愿望吧。
[kids chattering]
[girl squeals]
[孩子们喧哗声]
[女孩尖叫声]
One more.
[scattered clapping]
再来一次。
[零星的掌声]
Did you make a wish?
What’d you wish for?
你许愿了吗？
你许了什么愿？
[Becky] A bike.
Bike?
[贝姬] 一辆自行车。
自行车？
I don’t know if a bike
is exactly gonna fit
我不确定自行车
能不能正好装进
into this box, but...
rip it open.
这个盒子里，不过...
撕开它吧。
[kids chattering excitedly]
[孩子们兴奋地议论]
I’m gonna race ya. Yeah.
我要跟你比赛。对。
[chatter quiets]
[议论声渐弱]
What do you think?
你觉得怎么样？
It’s cool, right?
It’s my old Erector Set.
很酷吧？
这是我以前的组合玩具。
[baby babbling]
Let’s open it up.
[婴儿咿呀声]
我们打开吧。
There’s 200 pieces in here.
这里面有200个零件。
[pieces clattering]
[boy] No!
[零件哗啦作响]
[男孩] 不！
I mean, you got engines,
you got gears, pulleys,
我是说，这里面有发动机，
有齿轮、滑轮，
wheels, lights, switches.
轮子、灯、开关。
We can make almost anything
that we want with this thing.
我们几乎能用这东西
做出任何我们想要的东西。
Look, anything that you can
dream, we can make it, okay?
听着，只要你能
想到的，我们就能做出来，好吗？
Me and you. What do you say?
我和你。你觉得怎么样？
[kid clears throat]
[孩子清嗓子]
Can you make a bike
with it?
你能用它
造一辆自行车吗？
[noisemaker blows]
[吹响发声器]
[stammers] Yeah.
[结巴] 能。
Yeah.
能。
[Steve]
<i>I can’t believe the dude I knew</i>
[史蒂夫]
<i>真不敢相信我认识的那个82年的哥们儿</i>
<i>from the 82nd
can’t even afford a bike.</i>
<i>连辆自行车</i>
<i>都买不起。</i>
Well, tell me
how you’re doing so well.
那跟我说说
你混得这么好是怎么做到的。
Well, let me see.
让我想想。
Just this week, I got
two Japanese dudes passports.
就这周，我帮
两个日本人搞定了护照。
That’s 5K a pop.
每本五千块。
Five grand
for fake passports?
五千美金
办假护照？
No, for real passports.
Man...
不，是真护照。
老天...
Can I help you with that?
我能帮忙吗？
Hell motherfucking no,
you can’t.
当然他妈的不行，
你帮不了。
You can’t help me with shit.
你啥忙都帮不上。
[laughs] You crazy, man?
[笑] 你疯了吗？
You ain’t helping me do
a goddamn thing.
你休想帮我
干成任何事。
I don’t need your help.
我不需要你帮忙。
Plus, we already know
that doing things the right way
再说了，我们早就知道
循规蹈矩做事
is not your superpower.
可不是你的强项。
Whatever. That’s...
随便吧。那是...
Okay, then tell me
what my superpower is, then?
好吧，那你告诉我
我的超能力是什么？
Enlighten me, Buddha.
Mm.
给我开开窍啊，佛祖。
嗯。
What’s the flow rate
on that hose?
那根水管的流速是多少？
每分钟12加仑。
12 gallons per minute.
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼。
这条街上有多少栋房子？
How many houses is
on this street?
二十八栋。
那其中
Twenty-eight.
有多少家有烟囱？
And out of those,
how many got chimneys?
车库呢？
有多少家用的热泵
Garages?
而不是传统空调？
How many of ’em use a heat pump
instead of a traditional AC?
你是想让我
推销暖通空调系统
You want me
to sell HVAC systems
or something? Just...
还是怎么的？只是...
to sell HVAC systems
or something? Just...
No, no, man,
I’m trying to make a point.
不，不，老兄，
我是想说明一个观点。
Then make the point, please.
那就请直说吧。
Observation.
观察力。
Details.
细节。
You see shit
people don’t see.
你能看到
别人看不到的东西。
You got like a little
X-ray vision going on.
你就像是有那么点
X光透视眼一样。
What, you think they dropped
you off in Central America
’cause you a good shot?
怎么，你以为他们把你送到
中美洲
是因为你枪法好吗？
Is that what you think?
No. No...
你是这么想的吗？
不。不是...
No, they dropped you
because of what you see.
不，他们派你去
是因为你的洞察力。
Shit, if I had
a brain like yours,
靠，如果我有
你那样的头脑，
I’d be running
the whole goddamn world.
我早就统治
整个他妈的世界了。
You know, you the smartest
dumb nigga I ever known.
要知道，你是我见过最聪明的
傻老黑。
That shit crazy.
这也太离谱了。
You can stop filling up
that pool now.
你可以不用再往
那泳池里放水了。
Ain’t nobody gonna
get in there.
不会有人
进去游泳了。
That shit cold as hell.
[laughs]
那水冷得要命。
[笑]
[Jeffrey] <i>So, Mama
is probably gonna want to know</i>
[杰弗里] <i>所以，妈妈
很可能想知道</i>
how the party was, and,
yeah, I think we did our best.
派对办得怎么样，而且，
是的，我觉得我们尽力了。
What do you think?
你觉得呢？
Maybe we don’t mention
the pool. [chuckles]
也许我们别提
泳池的事。[轻笑]
[entry bell jingling]
[门铃叮当作响]
It’s the trying that counts, right?
重要的是努力尝试了，对吧？
[Becky] Mommy!
[贝姬] 妈妈！
Hi, birthday girl.
[Jeffrey sighs]
生日快乐，小寿星。
[杰弗里叹气]
How was your party?
派对怎么样？
[Becky]
Everybody did their best.
[贝姬]
大家都尽力了。
[Talena] Oh. Are you ready
for your other party?
[塔莱娜] 哦，你准备好
参加另一个派对了吗？
[car door closes]
[车门关闭]
Hi.
嗨。
[chuckles]
[轻笑]
How are you?
你好吗？
Hey, can I talk to you
for a second?
嘿，我能跟你
说会儿话吗？
Real-real quick, real quick.
很快就好，很快。
I know the last few months
haven’t been easy,
我知道最近几个月
并不轻松，
and we don’t have the things
that we actually need,
我们也没有
真正需要的东西，
and that’s my fault
and I own that.
这都是我的错
我承认。
Okay? I do, but I-I think
I have it figured out now.
好吗？我承认，但我觉得
我现在已经想明白了。
I just got to use
my superpower and
我只需要运用
我的超能力，
put my brain on what I want.
Your superpower?
把心思放在我想要的东西上。
你的超能力？
Your superpower?
Yes.
你的超能力？
是的。
[scoffs]
[嗤笑]
I can’t do this, Jeff.
Look-- No.
我做不到，杰夫。
听着——不行。
I’m done.
Come on,
please don’t do this.
我受够了。
拜托，
别这样。
Goodbye.
[car door closes]
再见。
[车门关闭]
[engine starts]
[引擎启动]
[sighs]
[叹气]
All right, banana head.
好了，香蕉脑袋。
Say goodbye.
说再见吧。
[Becky]
Love you!
[贝姬]
爱你！
Wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait!
等等，等等，
等等，等等！
[Jeffrey]
<i>I didn’t blame her
for laughing at me.</i>
[杰弗里]
<i>我没有怪她
嘲笑我。</i>
<i>For thinking I was a joke.</i>
<i>没有怪她觉得我是个笑话。</i>
<i>But there were things
that she didn’t know about me.</i>
<i>但她有些
关于我的事并不知情。</i>
<i>Things that weren’t so funny.</i>
[ladder clattering]
<i>一些并不那么好笑的事。</i>
[梯子哐当作响]
<i>Steve knew
what I was capable of.</i>
<i>史蒂夫知道
我的能耐。</i>
<i>I do see things
that other people don’t see.</i>
<i>我确实能看到
别人看不到的东西。</i>
<i>Like right now, I see that kid
climbing up that ladder,</i>
<i>比如现在，我看到那个孩子
正爬上那个梯子，</i>
<i>and I know that
under that flimsy roof</i>
<i>而且我知道
在那薄薄的屋顶下</i>
<i>is a machine that turns ground
beef and potatoes into money.</i>
<i>是一台能把牛肉末和土豆
牛肉和土豆变成钞票的机器。</i>
[entry bell jingles]
<i>With the same dining room,</i>
[门铃叮当作响]
<i>同样的餐厅，</i>
<i>the same deep fryers
with blinking red timer lights,</i>
<i>同样的油炸锅
闪着红光的定时器，</i>
<i>the same shake machine
with the same two flavors</i>
<i>同样的奶昔机
提供同样的两种口味，</i>
<i>and the same safe full of
weekend corporate burger money</i>
<i>还有同样的保险柜
装满周末的汉堡营业收入，</i>
<i>that no one was gonna miss.</i>
<i>没人会注意到少了。</i>
<i>They empty that safe
at the exact same time</i>
<i>他们会在
完全相同的时刻清空保险柜，</i>
<i>on Monday morning
at every single McDonald’s.</i>
<i>在每个星期一早上
每一家麦当劳。</i>
Hi. Welcome to McDonald’s.
您好，欢迎光临麦当劳。
Do you know what you want?
您决定好要点什么了吗？
Huh?
嗯？
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
对。对，对，对。
Um, yeah, I figured it out.
呃，是的，我想好了。
Thank you.
谢谢。
[Jeffrey]
<i>There are over 10,000</i>
[杰弗里]
<i>全美各地有超过一万家</i>
<i>almost identical McDonald’s
across the United States.</i>
<i>几乎一模一样的麦当劳</i>
餐厅。</i>
<i>Question was:
How many do you need to rob</i>
<i>问题是：</i>
你需要抢劫多少家</i>
<i>to get a real house,</i>
<i>才能买到一栋真正的房子，</i>
<i>buy your kids nice things
and win your family back?</i>
<i>给孩子们买好东西</i>
并赢回你的家庭？</i>
<i>Turns out,
the answer is 45.</i>
<i>事实证明，</i>
答案是45家。</i>
[reporter over TV]
<i>The Roofman has struck again,</i>
[电视记者]
<i>"屋顶大盗"再次作案，</i>
<i>cutting a hole through the roof
of this McDonald’s</i>
<i>他在费耶特维尔市麦迪逊街</i>
与朱厄尔街拐角处的</i>
<i>at the corner of Madison
and Jewell in Fayetteville.</i>
<i>这家麦当劳屋顶</i>
凿开了一个洞。</i>
<i>As you can imagine, this was
a terrifying experience.</i>
<i>可以想象，这真是</i>
一次可怕的经历。</i>
[Duane over TV] <i>He came in,
threw us in the freezer</i>
[杜安通过电视] <i>他进来后，</i>
把我们扔进了冰柜</i>
<i>and gave me his coat.</i>
<i>然后他把他的外套给了我。</i>
<i>He gave you his coat?
Yes.</i>
<i>他把他的外套给了你？</i>
是的。</i>
<i>Uh, yeah,
he didn’t want me to be cold.</i>
<i>呃，是的，</i>
<i>他不想让我冻着。</i>
<i>He was actually
really nice.</i>
<i>他实际上</i>
<i>人真的很好。</i>
[reporter] <i>Police believe
this is the same suspect</i>
[记者] <i>警方认为</i>
<i>这是同一个嫌疑人</i>
<i>who has been terrorizing
our local community</i>
<i>他一直在恐吓</i>
<i>我们的当地社区</i>
<i>with 45 incidents...</i>
<i>已有45起事件...</i>
Mm.
<i>...this past year alone.</i>
嗯。
<i>...仅在过去一年内。</i>
<i>We have a sketch
of the Roofman.</i>
<i>我们有一张</i>
<i>屋顶大盗的素描像。</i>
<i>He is always
wearing a mask.</i>
<i>他总是</i>
<i>戴着一个面具。</i>
<i>He’s described
as six-foot-two
with an athletic build.</i>
<i>据描述</i>
身高六英尺二英寸
体格健壮。</i>
What? <i>The Roofman has also struck</i>
什么？<i>屋顶窃贼还袭击过</i>
<i>Burger King,
Kentucky Fried Chicken...</i>
<i>汉堡王，
肯德基...</i>
Nice TV you got here, Jeff.
杰夫，你这台电视不错啊。
Big.
真大。
How you afford
something like that?
你怎么买得起
这种东西？
We got 15 hungry kids
out there
外面有15个饿坏了的孩子
在外面
that are
losing their minds
for cake.
他们
都快想蛋糕想疯了
想要吃蛋糕。
We got to go.
[TV volume increases]
我们得走了。
[电视音量提高]
[reporter] <i>...all of
these brazen incidents...</i>
[记者] <i>...所有这些
明目张胆的事件...</i>
We got to go.
Hold on, hold on.
我们得走了。
等等，等等。
We got to go
right now.
Let me see...
我们得走了
马上。
让我看看...
If she doesn’t
get her presents
right now...
如果她不能
马上拿到礼物
...
I want to know what’s going on
with the damn suspect.
我想知道那个该死的嫌犯
到底怎么回事。
...she’s gonna
lose her mind.
Can I see?
...她会
气疯的。
让我看看？
All right.
Why you turning it off?
好吧。
你干嘛关掉？
Wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait.
Don’t, don’t, don’t, d--
等等，等等，等等，
等等，等等，等等。
别，别，别，别--
[groans]
Come on.
[呻吟]
快点。
Let’s go.
我们走。
Goddamn, man.
该死的，老兄。
[mariachi band playing
lively music]
[墨西哥街头乐队演奏
欢快的音乐]
[playing "Happy Birthday"]
[演奏《生日快乐歌》]
[band and guests]
<i>♪ Happy birthday to you ♪</i>
[乐队与宾客]
<i>♪ 祝你生日快乐 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Happy birthday ♪</i>
<i>♪ 生日快乐 ♪</i>
<i>♪ To you ♪</i>
<i>♪ 祝你 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Happy birthday, bandida ♪</i>
<i>♪ 生日快乐，bandida ♪</i>
<i>♪ Happy birthday to you ♪</i>
You.
<i>♪ 祝你生日快乐 ♪</i>
你。
[song continues
with lyrics in Spanish]
[歌曲继续
西班牙语歌词]
[whoops]
[song ends]
[欢呼声]
[歌曲结束]
[cheering]
[whistling]
[喝彩声]
[口哨声]
Let’s go!
我们走吧！
All right.
好的。
Big breath, big wish.
Here we go.
深吸一口气，许个大愿。
开始吧。
[cheering loudly]
[大声欢呼]
All right, we’re gonna do
this one first this year.
好的，我们今年要
先做这个。
Big things
in little boxes.
小盒子里
装大礼。
[Becky]
What is this?
[贝姬]
这是什么？
A garage door opener?
车库门遥控器？
Why’d you give me
a garage door opener?
你为什么给我
一个车库门遥控器？
I don’t know.
I just couldn’t think
of anywhere else
我不知道。
我只是想不出
还有什么别的地方
to put, uh,
the saber-toothed tiger,
so...
可以放，呃，
那只剑齿虎，
所以...
I don’t know. I couldn’t put it
in the kitchen, could I?
我不知道。我总不能
把它放厨房吧？
[whispering]
So, where is it?
[低声说]
所以，它在哪儿？
[band playing "El Fuereño"]
[cheering]
[乐队演奏《外地人》]
[欢呼声]
[band continues playing]
[乐队继续演奏]
You’re the best daddy
in the whole entire world!
你是全世界
最棒的爸爸！
[laughing]
[笑声]
Now, go ahead, get on it.
来，快坐上去吧。
[vehicles approaching]
[车辆驶近声]
[Becky]
I love it.
[贝姬]
我太喜欢了。
[tires screech]
[siren chirps]
[轮胎摩擦声]
[警笛鸣响]
[bicycle bell jingles]
[自行车铃叮当声]
[indistinct
police radio chatter]
[模糊的
警用对讲机通话声]
How you guys doing?
各位还好吗？
We’re looking
for Jeffrey Manchester.
我们正在找
杰弗里·曼彻斯特。
This about the registration?
是为了登记的事吗？
Yeah, I got it
right in here.
One second.
对，我这就
就在这里面。
稍等。
["El Fuereño" continues
with lyrics in Spanish]
["外乡人"继续播放
歌词为西班牙语]
Stop.
停下。
You’re under arrest!
你被捕了！
[Steve]
Whoa! Hey, hey, hey.
[史蒂夫]
哇！嘿，嘿，嘿。
[grunts]
[闷哼声]
[officers shouting]
[警察喊叫声]
["El Fuereño" continues
with lyrics in Spanish]
["外乡人"继续播放
歌词为西班牙语]
[siren wailing]
[警笛长鸣]
[officer]
Freeze! You’re under arrest!
[警官]
不许动！你被捕了！
[officers shouting]
[警察喊叫声]
[grunting]
[用力声]
[song ends]
[歌曲结束]
[judge]
Mr. Manchester, please rise.
[法官]
曼彻斯特先生，请起立。
The State has proved
beyond the defined burden
本州已证实
超出法定举证标准
that you committed
the crime of robbery
with a dangerous weapon.
你犯下了
持械抢劫罪
使用了危险武器
I’d like to take in
consideration
我愿考虑
纳入考量
your service to this country
in the armed forces
你曾为国效力
在武装部队服役
and the impact of your children
losing a father.
以及你的孩子们
失去父亲的影响
<i>Now, I know
you got everyone fooled</i>
<i>我深知
<i>你骗过了所有人</i>
<i>thinking you’re a nice guy,
but I know you’re a menace.</i>
<i>让人以为你是个好人</i>
<i>但我清楚你是个祸害</i>
Although you’re only
being tried for one robbery,
尽管此次审判
仅针对一桩抢劫案
we know you’ve done many more.
但我们知道你罪行累累
And so the prosecution
has requested
因此检方
要求
that I issue a single count
of felony kidnapping
我宣布一项指控
重罪绑架
for each victim
you locked in the freezer.
针对每位受害者
被你锁在冷库里的
Let the record state that
on the 4th of February, 2004,
记录显示
2004年2月4日
you’re hereby sentenced
to 180 months
现判处你
180个月
for each of the three victims,
针对三名受害者每人
for a total of 540 months
or 45 years
总计540个月
即45年
in the North Carolina
Department of Corrections.
在北卡罗来纳州
惩戒署服刑
Mr. Sheriff,
he is in your custody.
警长先生
此人交由你羁押
[gavel bangs]
This concludes this case.
[法槌敲击声]
本案审理结束
[gallery murmuring]
[lawyer whispering]
[旁听席议论声]
[律师低语声]
[indistinct chatter]
[模糊的交谈声]
[cell door rattles, clanks]
[牢门哐当作响]
[phone line ringing]
[电话铃响]
[line clicks]
[Becky over phone] <i>Hi, Daddy.</i>
[电话接通声]
[贝基来电] <i>嗨，爸爸。</i>
<i>I really missed you.</i>
<i>我好想你。</i>
Miss you, too.
I miss you a lot.
我也想你。
我非常想你。
<i>Hey, did you get the letter
that I drew
the big ol’ house on it?</i>
<i>嘿，你收到那封信了吗</i>
<i>就是我画了</i>
<i>那栋大房子的那封？</i>
No.
没有。
<i>Well, maybe
it hasn’t arrived.
Ask Mama.</i>
<i>嗯，也许</i>
<i>信还没到。</i>
<i>问问妈妈。</i>
<i>Mom says
she’ll save the letters.</i>
<i>妈妈说</i>
<i>她会把信都收好。</i>
<i>When I’m old enough,
I can read them.</i>
<i>等我长大些，</i>
<i>我就可以看了。</i>
No, no. That is not...
that is not right.
不，不。这样不对...
这样不对。
These letters are for,
they’re for right now.
这些信是为了，
它们是为了现在。
[Talena] Tell him
we’re cutting the cord.
[塔莱娜] 告诉他
我们要切断联系了。
They said
we have to cut the cord.
他们说
我们必须切断联系。
[Jeffrey]
<i>No, we’re not cutting the cord.</i>
[杰弗里]
<i>不，我们不会切断联系。</i>
[stammers] <i>Who said that?</i>
[结巴地] <i>谁说的？</i>
<i>We went to a meeting for
families with dads in prison.</i>
<i>我们去参加了一个
为父亲在监狱的家庭举办的会议。</i>
Okay, well, that’s good.
好吧，那很好。
That’s really good.
What’d they say there?
那真的很好。
他们在那里说了什么？
<i>That it isn’t my fault.
It’s your fault.</i>
<i>说这不是我的错。
是你的错。</i>
<i>And to let you go, all the way,</i>
<i>并且要让你走，彻底地，</i>
<i>’cause you’ll never come home,
even if you say you will.</i>
<i>因为你永远不会回家，</i>
即使你说你会。</i>
Look,
that last part is not--
that is very, very wrong.
听着，
最后那部分不是——
那是非常非常错误的。
[recorded voice]
<i>You have 60 seconds remaining.</i>
[录音语音]
<i>您还剩60秒。</i>
<i>Hey, can you put
your mom on for a second?</i>
<i>嘿，你能让你
妈妈听一下电话吗？</i>
He wants to talk to you.
他想和你说话。
No. Tell him that
you have to hang up.
不，告诉他
你得挂电话了。
Gary’s gonna help you
with your homework.
加里会帮你
辅导作业。
She doesn’t want
to talk to you.
她不想
和你说话。
<i>She said I have to get off
and do homework.</i>
<i>她说我得挂电话
去做作业了。</i>
<i>Gary is going to help me.</i>
<i>加里会帮我。</i>
Gary? Who’s Gary?
加里？加里是谁？
<i>Mom’s friend.</i>
<i>妈妈的朋友。</i>
Huh. Mom’s got
a new friend named Gary.
呵，妈妈交了
个新朋友叫加里。
That’s-that’s fun.
这-这挺有意思的。
[Talena]
It’s okay, sweetheart.
You can tell him.
[塔莱娜]
没事的，宝贝。
你可以告诉他。
<i>Um, okay, I’m gonna call you
tomorrow at the same time</i>
<i>嗯，好吧，我会在</i>
<i>老时间给你打电话</i>
<i>I always do, all right?</i>
<i>和往常一样，好吗？</i>
<i>They said no more calls.</i>
<i>他们说不准再打电话了。</i>
No, no.
Who said that? No.
不，不。
谁说的？不行。
[Talena]
Hang up the phone.
[塔莱娜]
挂电话。
[Gary]
It’s okay, Becky.
[加里]
没事的，贝基。
You can hang up now.
[Jeffrey] <i>Hang up?</i>
你现在可以挂了。
[杰弗里] <i>挂电话？</i>
Is that Gary?
Put him on the phone
right now.
那是加里吗？
让他接电话
马上。
[Talena]
<i>Hang up. Hang up.</i>
[塔莱娜]
<i>挂断。快挂断。</i>
Put Gary or your mom
on the phone right now,
Becky, okay?
让加里或者你妈妈
马上接电话，
贝姬，好吗？
[Becky]
<i>I have to hang up.</i>
Hey.
[贝姬]
<i>我得挂电话了。</i>
喂。
<i>Listen to me,
I’m coming home.</i>
<i>听我说，
我要回家了。</i>
<i>Tell your brothers
I’m coming home.</i>
<i>告诉你的兄弟们
我要回家了。</i>
<i>And we don’t say goodbye,
’cause goodbye means going away</i>
<i>我们不说再见，
因为再见意味着离开，</i>
and going away means
forgetting, and we’re...
而离开意味着
遗忘，而我们...
[click, dial tone drones]
We’re-- H-Hello?
[咔嗒声，电话忙音响起]
我们-- 喂？喂？
Hello?
喂？
B... Becky?
贝... 贝姬？
[prisoner] <i>Why is you
still thinking about them?</i>
[囚犯] <i>你为什么还
还在想他们？
<i>You got to let that go.</i>
你得放下这些念头。
Ain’t no
getting out of here.
根本没可能
离开这里。
Get that idea
out your head.
把这个念头
从你脑子里赶出去。
[Jeffrey] <i>Every prisoner
wants the same thing:</i>
[杰弗里] 每个囚犯
都想要一样东西：
<i>to get out of prison.</i>
[tools buzzing]
就是离开监狱。
[工具嗡嗡声]
<i>And they think
that the way out
is through a wall</i>
他们认为
越狱的方法
是凿穿墙壁
<i>or over a fence.</i>
或是翻越围栏。
<i>But the guards
got that covered.</i>
但狱警们
早就防着这些了。
<i>The way out of prison
is through the people.</i>
真正的出路
在于利用人际关系。
<i>Prison was
just another building</i>
监狱不过是
另一座充斥着
<i>full of systems
and routines.</i>
<i>充满了各种制度
和例行程序。</i>
<i>Keep the routine,
and the guards
won’t get suspicious.</i>
<i>保持例行公事，
警卫们
就不会起疑心。</i>
<i>If you’re nice enough,
if you’re useful,</i>
<i>如果你足够友善，
如果你有用处，</i>
<i>they forget
you’re in there
for a reason.</i>
<i>他们就会忘记
你被关在这里
是有原因的。</i>
<i>And when they stop
watching you,</i>
<i>而当他们停止
监视你时，</i>
<i>you can start
watching them.</i>
<i>你就可以开始
监视他们。</i>
You smell that?
你闻到了吗？
Smells like you’re leaking.
闻起来像是你在漏油。
How ’bout
checking it out
for me.
不如
帮我
检查一下。
Yes, sir.
See if you see
anything.
是的，长官。
看看你能否看到
什么异常
Yeah.
嗯
Doesn’t look too bad
just yet.
目前看起来还不算太糟
暂时
I don’t know--
it’ll probably get you back
to where you’re going.
我不确定——
但应该能撑到你
要去的地方
All right.
Well, come on out of there.
好的
先出来吧
行
Yeah, you better
tell your maintenance guy.
你最好
跟维修人员说一声
You might need a new gasket.
可能需要换个新垫圈
I appreciate it, man.
Yes, sir.
谢了兄弟
好的
Have a good one.
You, too.
祝你顺利
你也是
[truck door closes]
[engine starts]
[卡车门关闭]
[引擎启动]
[tools buzzing]
[工具嗡嗡作响]
[whistling a tune]
[吹着口哨]
[door opens]
[门开了]
[tools buzzing]
[truck back-up alarm beeping]
[工具嗡嗡作响]
[卡车倒车警报声]
[truck engine rumbling]
[卡车引擎轰鸣]
Yeah. Straight back.
对，直接倒进来。
Two boxes.
[Jeffrey] Yep.
两个箱子。
[杰弗里] 嗯。
Two benches.
Yes, sir.
两条长凳。
好的，先生。
All right.
行了。
Shut her down.
熄火吧。
She’s all yours,
Mr. Cummings.
Thank you, bud.
这车交给你了，
卡明斯先生。
谢了，伙计。
Hey, smells
like you fixed it.
嘿，闻着味儿
像是修好了。
[chuckles] Good catch.
[轻笑] 好眼力。
All right, drive safe.
All right,
have a good one.
好了，开车注意安全。
好的，
祝你顺利。
[truck door closes]
[卡车门关闭]
[engine starts]
[引擎启动]
[engine idling]
[low, indistinct chatter]
[引擎空转]
[低沉模糊的谈话声]
[chatter continues]
[谈话声持续]
[brakes hissing]
[engine rumbling]
[刹车嘶嘶声]
[引擎轰鸣声]
[tires screech]
[brakes hiss]
[轮胎摩擦声]
[刹车嘶嘶声]
[truck door opens]
[卡车门打开]
Jesus.
天啊。
Phew.
呼。
[belt jangles]
[zipper whizzes]
[皮带叮当声]
[拉链嗖嗖声]
[sighs]
[叹气声]
[belt jangles]
[皮带叮当声]
[zipper whizzes]
[拉链嗖嗖声]
[engine starts]
[引擎启动]
[dog barking in distance]
[insects chirping]
[远处狗吠声]
[虫鸣声]
[Jeffrey laughing softly]
[杰弗里轻声笑]
[Jeffrey whispering]
Yeah.
[杰弗里低语]
嗯。
Yeah, pedal, pedal, pedal,
pedal, pedal.
对，踩，踩，踩，
踩，踩。
[Jeffrey laughing softly]
[杰弗里轻声笑]
[grunts]
[闷哼声]
["S’Cudjo" by Zé Manel playing]
[播放着 Zé Manel 的《S’Cudjo》]
[phone ringing]
[电话铃响]
Hello?
喂？
[Jeffrey over phone]
<i>Steve. It’s me.</i>
[杰弗里在电话里]
<i>史蒂夫。是我。</i>
Jeff, Jeff, what the fuck
are you doing calling me, man?
杰夫，杰夫，你他妈
给我打电话干什么，老兄？
You all over the goddamn news
and shit.
你他妈都上了所有新闻
之类的了。
Look, I got to get
out of the country.
听着，我得
离开这个国家。
I’m thinking, like,
Brazil or Venezuela.
我在想，比如，
巴西或者委内瑞拉。
Somewhere with a beach
and no extradition.
找个有海滩
又没有引渡条约的地方。
[Steve]
<i>God, you sound fucking crazy.</i>
[史蒂夫]
<i>天啊，你听起来简直疯了。</i>
[stammers]
I know. I’m sorry.
[结巴]
我知道。对不起。
<i>Don’t do no stupid shit
like go see your family.</i>
<i>别干蠢事
比如去看你的家人。</i>
<i>Hide. All right?</i>
Okay. Okay. I’ll hide.
<i>躲起来。好吗？</i>
好的。好的。我会躲起来。
<i>Don’t call back
for another month.</i>
<i>别再打电话
至少一个月。</i>
All right,
I’m-a call you in a month.
好吧，
我一个月后打给你。
And don’t call
my motherfucking phone again.
还有，别再打
我这个该死的电话了。
You got it? A’ight.
明白了吗？好的。
[click, dial tone drones]
Steve?
[咔嗒声，拨号音持续响起]
史蒂夫？
St--
史——
[sighs]
[叹气]
[cart wheels rattling]
[手推车车轮嘎吱作响]
[music playing
over vehicle stereo]
[音乐播放
通过车载音响]
[light music playing
over speakers]
[轻音乐播放
通过扬声器]
[Mitch] You.
[girl] A lot.
[米奇] 你。
[女孩] 很多。
[Mitch]
A lot? We have-- Yep.
What do you want?
[米奇]
很多？我们有——是的。
你想要什么？
[girl] A monkey.
A monkey?
[女孩] 一只猴子。
一只猴子？
[kids chattering]
Wait a minute.
[孩子们叽叽喳喳]
等一下。
[boy] Turtle.
[Mitch] Turtle.
[男孩] 乌龟。
[米奇] 乌龟。
What--
and what do you want?
[girl] Candy.
什么——
那你想要什么？
[女孩] 糖果。
Candy?
糖果？
We got a lot of candy.
我们有很多糖果。
Uh, um, sir,
we’re closing here
in ten minutes.
呃，嗯，先生，
我们这里
十分钟后关门。
Sir?
Yeah, no problem.
先生？
好的，没问题。
[toys beeping, chirping]
[玩具发出哔哔声、啾啾声]
I got you.
我帮你搞定。
[toy beeping]
[玩具哔哔响]
[toy phone ringing]
[玩具电话铃声]
[toy gun firing]
[玩具枪射击声]
[indistinct chatter
over speakers]
[模糊的嘈杂人声
通过喇叭传出]
[toy laser gun firing]
[玩具激光枪射击声]
[door creaks]
[门吱呀作响]
[door closes]
[门关上]
[panting]
[喘气声]
[shoes squeak on toilet]
[鞋子在马桶上吱吱作响]
[grunting]
[咕哝声]
[door opens]
[门开了]
[indistinct
police radio chatter]
[模糊的
警察无线电通话声]
[door closes]
[门关了]
[indistinct police radio
chatter continues]
[模糊的警察无线电
通话声持续]
[officer over radio]
<i>Zero, three, six,</i>
[警官通过无线电]
<i>零，三，六，</i>
<i>five, nine, eight, two.</i>
<i>五，九，八，二。</i>
[footsteps approaching]
[脚步声接近]
[indistinct police radio
chatter continues]
[模糊的警察无线电
通话声持续]
[officer] Bathroom’s clear.
[door opens, closes]
[警官] 洗手间安全。
[门开，门关]
[exhales]
[呼气声]
[Mitch over speakers]
<i>Attention,</i>
[米奇通过广播]
<i>各位顾客请注意，</i>
<i>Toys "R" Us customers.</i>
<i>玩具反斗城的顾客们。</i>
<i>Our store will be closing
in five minutes.</i>
五分钟后关门。</i>
<i>So, if you are not a toy
or an employee,</i>
<i>所以，如果您不是玩具</i>
<i>也不是员工，</i>
<i>please bring your purchases
up to the front.</i>
<i>请将您选购的商品</i>
<i>带到前台来。</i>
<i>Whether you are a kid
or a parent</i>
<i>无论您是孩子</i>
<i>还是家长，</i>
<i>or an uncle or a friend
making a dream come true,</i>
<i>是叔叔阿姨还是朋友，</i>
<i>是来帮人实现梦想，</i>
<i>it is time
to make your choices</i>
<i>现在都该</i>
<i>做出选择了，</i>
<i>and meet us
at the register up front.</i>
<i>并到前面的</i>
<i>收银台来找我们。</i>
<i>If you can’t decide tonight,
don’t worry.</i>
<i>如果您今晚无法决定，</i>
<i>别担心。</i>
<i>We promise you
we will be here tomorrow,</i>
<i>我们向您保证</i>
<i>我们明天还会在这里，</i>
just as long as you promise us
to never grow up.
<i>只要您也向我们保证</i>
<i>永远不要长大。</i>
[exhales quietly]
[轻声呼气]
[clattering]
[哐当作响]
[toy squeaks]
[玩具吱吱作响]
[shoes squeaking softly]
[鞋子轻柔地吱吱作响]
[doors creaking]
[门吱嘎作响]
[unzips backpack]
[拉开背包拉链]
[exhales]
[呼气]
[news anchor]
<i>Jeffrey Manchester, also known</i>
[新闻主播]
<i>杰弗里·曼彻斯特，又名</i>
<i>as the Roofman, escaped
from Brown Creek Prison
earlier today.</i>
<i>“飞贼”，已于今日早些时候</i>
从布朗克里克监狱逃脱。</i>
</i>
<i>Tonight, he’s still
out there somewhere.</i>
<i>今晚，他仍然</i>
在逃，下落不明。</i>
[reporter] <i>Authorities
discovered Manchester,</i>
[记者] <i>当局</i>
<i>发现曼彻斯特</i>
<i>who was serving 45 years for
armed robbery and kidnapping,</i>
<i>（他因持械抢劫和绑架</i>
<i>正在服45年刑期）</i>
<i>was missing this afternoon...</i>
<i>于今天下午点名时失踪...</i>
Ha.
<i>...during a routine head count.</i>
哈。
<i>...在一次例行点名中。</i>
<i>Correction officers
do not know the method</i>
<i>惩教官员
不知道具体的逃脱方式</i>
<i>or exact time
of Manchester’s escape...</i>
<i>或确切时间</i>
<i>曼彻斯特的逃脱...</i>
They still don’t know
how I got out.
他们仍然不知道
我是怎么出来的。
<i>...but believe he may still be
in the Charlotte area.</i>
<i>...但认为他可能仍在</i>
<i>夏洛特地区。</i>
No, no, no. I’m-I’m long gone.
[Scheimreif]
<i>We believe he fled</i>
不，不，不。我——我早就远走高飞了。
[沙伊姆赖夫]
<i>我们相信他是在</i>
<i>sometime between 12:00 and 4:00
this afternoon.</i>
<i>今天中午12点到下午4点之间的某个时间</i>
<i>逃离的。</i>
<i>He’s a very smart individual.
Super intelligent.</i>
<i>他是个非常聪明的人。
超级聪明。</i>
<i>Probably genius level.</i>
<i>可能达到天才级别。</i>
<i>But he’s also
an absolute idiot.</i>
<i>但他同时也是</i>
<i>一个十足的蠢货。</i>
<i>We believe that the suspect
could be armed.</i>
<i>我们相信嫌疑人</i>
可能持有武器。</i>
<i>And he has a history
of violent behavior.</i>
<i>并且他有</i>
暴力行为的历史。</i>
What?
[reporter] <i>Police are asking</i>
什么？
[记者] <i>警方请求</i>
<i>if you see someone
who looks like Manchester,</i>
<i>如果您看到</i>
长得像曼彻斯特的人，</i>
<i>please call authorities
and do not confront him.</i>
<i>请致电当局</i>
并且不要与他正面冲突。</i>
[birds chirping]
[鸟鸣声]
[busy chatter]
[嘈杂的谈话声]
[chair creaking]
[椅子吱呀声]
[Jeffrey exhales]
[杰弗里呼气声]
[chuckles]
[轻笑]
Okay.
好的。
All right.
好吧。
Yeah.
是的。
[chuckles]
[轻笑]
Password:
one, two, three, four,
密码：
一，二，三，四，
five, six.
五、六。
[mutters]
[低声自语]
Whoa. Yeah.
哇。是的。
[Jeffrey] <i>Most guys,
when they escape,</i>
[杰弗里] <i>大多数人，
当他们逃跑时，</i>
<i>get caught
in the first few hours.</i>
<i>会在头几个小时内
就被抓住。</i>
<i>They go as far as they can
as fast as they can.</i>
<i>他们会尽可能远地逃跑
尽可能快地逃跑。</i>
[knocks]
<i>And that never works.</i>
[敲门声]
<i>而那从来都不管用。</i>
<i>The trick is to stop.</i>
<i>诀窍在于停下来。</i>
<i>Find a place
no one will look.</i>
<i>找一个
没人会注意的地方。</i>
["Free" by Ultra Naté playing]
[Ultra Naté的《Free》播放中]
[mutters]
[低声自语]
[Jeffrey] <i>Sometimes,
the best hiding places
are in plain sight.</i>
[杰弗里] <i>有时候，
最好的藏身之处
就在最显眼的地方。</i>
<i>A place where people are
too preoccupied to see you.</i>
<i>一个人来人往
<i>一个人们过于专注而看不见你的地方。</i>
<i>So I kept quiet as a mouse.</i>
<i>所以我像老鼠一样保持安静。</i>
<i>But not at night.</i>
<i>但不是在晚上。</i>
<i>I owned the night.</i>
<i>夜晚属于我。</i>
<i>♪ Where did we go wrong? ♪</i>
<i>♪ 我们哪里出错了？ ♪</i>
[reporter]
<i>The manhunt for the Roofman</i>
[记者]
<i>对“飞贼”的搜捕</i>
<i>enters its third day.</i>
<i>已进入第三天。</i>
[Jeffrey] <i>People
have short attention spans.</i>
[杰弗里] <i>人们的</i>
<i>注意力持续时间很短。</i>
<i>After a while,
they get bored.</i>
<i>过一阵子，</i>
<i>他们就会感到厌倦。</i>
<i>I figured I had to
be quiet for about a month,
give or take.</i>
<i>我估计我需要</i>
<i>保持安静大约一个月，</i>
<i>或多或少。</i>
[reporter]
<i>Still no leads from police
on the whereabouts</i>
[记者]
<i>警方仍未获得</i>
<i>关于</i>
<i>of escaped convict
Jeffrey Manchester,</i>
<i>逃犯</i>
<i>杰弗里·曼彻斯特下落的线索，</i>
<i>as the manhunt enters
its eighth day.</i>
<i>随着搜捕进入
第八天。</i>
[Jeffrey] <i>One time,
when I was in the 82nd,</i>
[Jeffrey] <i>有一次，
当我在第82空降师时，</i>
<i>I spent 30 days
in the woods</i>
<i>我在丛林里
待了30天</i>
<i>surviving off of
rainwater and grubs.</i>
<i>靠雨水
和蛴螬活了下来。</i>
<i>Your body doesn’t need much
to keep going.</i>
<i>你的身体不需要太多东西
就能维持下去。</i>
<i>It’s your brain
that you have to
take care of.</i>
<i>关键是你的大脑
需要
好好照顾。</i>
<i>If you can make your brain
imagine a better place,</i>
<i>如果你能让大脑
想象一个更好的地方，</i>
<i>it can get you
through anything.</i>
<i>它就能帮你
渡过任何难关。</i>
<i>Just pick any place
but where you are.</i>
<i>随便选个地方，
只要不是你现在所处之地。</i>
<i>Like a beach on an ocean.</i>
<i>比如大洋边的海滩。</i>
<i>A place where
your kids can visit</i>
<i>一个地方，</i>
你的孩子们可以拜访</i>
<i>after everyone else
forgets you.</i>
<i>在所有人都</i>
忘记你之后。</i>
[reporter]
<i>Nearly two weeks</i>
[记者]
<i>将近两周</i>
<i>since Jeffrey Manchester
escaped</i>
<i>自从杰弗里·曼彻斯特</i>
逃脱</i>
<i>from Brown Creek Penitentiary.</i>
<i>从布朗克里克监狱。</i>
<i>Police have set up
roadblocks,</i>
<i>警方已经设置了</i>
路障，</i>
<i>concerned Manchester
may still be in the area.</i>
<i>担心曼彻斯特</i>
可能仍在附近。</i>
<i>Sergeant,
I’m with Channel 6 News.</i>
<i>警官，</i>
我是第六频道新闻的。</i>
<i>Jeffrey Manchester’s
still missing.</i>
<i>杰弗里·曼彻斯特</i>
仍然在逃。</i>
<i>Do you think he could be
in Charlotte?</i>
<i>你认为他可能在</i>
夏洛特吗？</i>
[Scheimreif]
<i>He might’ve kept moving,</i>
[沙伊姆赖夫]
<i>他可能已经继续逃窜，</i>
<i>but we’re not gonna give up
on the possibility</i>
<i>但我们不会放弃</i>
这种可能性</i>
<i>that he still might be
hiding out here</i>
<i>即他可能仍然</i>
藏匿在此地</i>
<i>in Mecklenburg County.</i>
<i>梅克伦堡县境内。</i>
<i>And when he tries to run,
we’ll be ready.</i>
<i>一旦他试图逃跑，</i>
我们已严阵以待。</i>
Good luck.
祝你好运。
<i>♪ Never trust another ♪</i>
<i>♪ 永远别信任他人 ♪</i>
<i>♪ ’Cause they’re all out
to getcha ♪</i>
<i>♪ 因为他们全都</i>
想要陷害你 ♪</i>
<i>♪ We have to live
in this world together ♪</i>
<i>♪ 我们必须共同</i>
生活在这世界 ♪</i>
<i>♪ ’Gether ♪</i>
<i>♪ 共同 ♪</i>
<i>♪ If we open up our heart,
love can finally start ♪</i>
<i>♪ 若我们敞开心扉，</i>
爱终将萌芽 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Come on and try ♪</i>
<i>♪ 来吧 尝试吧 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Now’s the time ♪</i>
<i>♪ 时机已到 ♪</i>
<i>♪ ’Cause you’re free ♪</i>
<i>♪ 因为你自由了 ♪</i>
<i>♪ To do what you want to do ♪</i>
<i>♪ 去做你想做的事 ♪</i>
<i>♪ You got to live your life ♪</i>
<i>♪ 你该过自己的生活 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Do what you want to do ♪</i>
<i>♪ 做你想做的事 ♪</i>
[shoes squeak]
[鞋子吱吱作响]
<i>♪ Do what you want ♪</i>
<i>♪ 随心所欲 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Do what you want to do ♪</i>
<i>♪ 做你想做的事 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Do what you want ♪</i>
<i>♪ 随心而行 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Do what you want to do ♪</i>
[song fades]
<i>♪ 做你想做的事 ♪</i>
[歌声渐弱]
[grunts]
[闷哼声]
[Leigh over headphones]
<i>One quick question.</i>
[莉通过耳机]
<i>有个小问题。</i>
[Mitch over headphones]
<i>Uh, yeah.</i>
[米奇通过耳机]
<i>呃，是的。</i>
[Leigh] <i>Okay. I just
wanted to talk to you
about my hours.</i>
[莉] <i>好的。我只是
想跟你谈谈
我的工作时间。</i>
[chuckles] <i>Um...</i>
[轻笑] <i>嗯...</i>
<i>I need every other weekend off.</i>
<i>我需要隔周休息一个周末。</i>
[Mitch]
<i>I’m confused.</i>
[米奇]
<i>我很困惑。</i>
<i>First you ask me
for a job,</i>
<i>你先向我</i>
<i>要工作，</i>
<i>and now you’re asking me
for time off.</i>
<i>现在又向我</i>
<i>要休假。</i>
[Leigh]
Well, you know,
嗯，你知道，
I’m a team player... Yeah.
我是个有团队精神的人...是的。
...but, um, I’m also a mom.
...但是，呃，我也是个母亲。
I know.
我知道。
Okay. Well...
I do.
好吧。嗯...
我明白。
Uh...
You-you reminded me.
呃...
你-你提醒了我。
I got a divorce
six months ago, so...
我六个月前离婚了，
所以...
<i>it’s really hard for me to
balance everything right now</i>
<i>对我来说，现在真的很难</i>
<i>平衡所有事情</i>
<i>with work and my girls
and my ex.</i>
<i>既要工作，又要照顾我的女儿们</i>
<i>还要面对我的前夫。</i>
Oh, come on. [mutters]
<i>The custody situation is:</i>
哦，得了吧。[低声咕哝]
<i>监护权的情况是：</i>
They have, you know,
one weekend him,
one weekend me.
他们，你知道的，
一个周末跟他，
一个周末跟我。
I don’t want to bore you
with my personal problems.
我不想用我的个人问题
来烦你。
Good, good. ’Cause I
don’t want to be bored
by your personal problems.
很好，很好。因为我
可不想被你的个人问题
烦到。
If this is
a Toys "R" Us problem,
then I’m interested.
如果这是
一个玩具反斗城的问题，
那我倒有兴趣。
But personal problems
belong on personal time.
但个人问题
应该留在私人时间处理。
[clicks tongue]
[咂舌]
Thank you, Leigh.
Got to get back to payroll.
谢谢你，莉。
得回去处理工资单了。
Work, work, work, work,
work, work, work.
工作，工作，工作，工作，
工作，工作，工作。
<i>Good to see you.</i>
<i>很高兴见到你。</i>
[Jeffrey] What a dick.
<i>Thanks, Mitch.</i>
[Jeffrey] 真是个混蛋。
<i>谢谢你，米奇。</i>
<i>Okay.</i>
<i>好吧。</i>
[door closes]
[Mitch] <i>Unbelievable.</i>
[门关上了]
[Mitch] <i>难以置信。</i>
Yeah, you’re
an unbelievable dick.
是啊，你
真是个难以置信的混蛋。
<i>I know you’re a mom.
You mentioned it before.</i>
<i>我知道你是个母亲。
你之前提过。</i>
<i>Mom card. Unbelievable.</i>
<i>打母亲牌。真行啊。</i>
[stammers]
[结结巴巴地]
[Jeffrey]
Dollar sign, U,
美元符号，U，
C, C, E,
C，C，E，
dollar sign, dollar sign.
美元符号，美元符号。
That’s the dumbest password
I’ve ever...
这是我听过
最蠢的密码...
I’ve ever heard of.
我闻所未闻。
"$ucce$$."
"$ucce$。"
[computer chimes]
Heh.
[电脑提示音响起]
呵。
[mouse clicking]
[鼠标点击声]
[clicking tongue]
[咂舌声]
[goofy voice]
We found Leigh.
[搞怪腔调]
我们找到利了。
Saturday.
周六。
Goodbye.
再见。
Boop, boop, boop, boop, boop,
boop, boop, boop, boop, boop.
嘟，嘟，嘟，嘟，嘟，
嘟，嘟，嘟，嘟，嘟。
[pops lips, clicks tongue]
[咂嘴，弹舌声]
You have the day off now.
[pops lips]
你今天放假了。
[咂嘴声]
Voilà.
瞧。
[news theme plays]
[announcer]
<i>The news starts now.</i>
[新闻主题曲播放]
[播音员]
<i>新闻现在开始。</i>
[news anchor] <i>More than
30,000 folks are expected</i>
[新闻主播] <i>预计将有超过
三万人</i>
<i>to crowd into town.</i>
<i>涌入小镇。</i>
[reporter] <i>...came up with
the idea "Babe Wash."</i>
[记者] <i>...想出了</TRANSLATE_0]
这个"宝贝洗车"的主意。</i></TRANSLATE_1]
<i>And the bikinis do
bring in the business.</i>
<i>而这些比基尼确实</i></TRANSLATE_2]
<i>带来了生意。</i></TRANSLATE_3]
[reporter 2] <i>The biggest
celebrations of the Fourth</i>
[记者2] <i>最盛大的</i></TRANSLATE_4]
<i>独立日庆祝活动</i></TRANSLATE_5]
<i>take place in the skies
right behind me.</i>
<i>正在我身后的</i></TRANSLATE_6]
<i>天空中上演。</i></TRANSLATE_7]
[Jeffrey]
<i>People get bored</i>
[杰弗里]</TRANSLATE_8]
<i>人们很快就会</i></TRANSLATE_9]
<i>with last week’s news.</i>
<i>对上周的新闻感到厌倦。</i></TRANSLATE_10]
<i>Pretty soon,
they can’t even remember
why they know your face.</i>
<i>很快地，</i></TRANSLATE_11]
<i>他们甚至记不起</i></TRANSLATE_12]
<i>为何认得你的脸了。</i></TRANSLATE_13]
<i>Even cops lose interest
unless you really piss ’em off.</i>
<i>就连警察也会失去兴趣，</i></TRANSLATE_14]
<i>除非你真的惹毛了他们。</i></TRANSLATE_15]
<i>Everybody forgets you
eventually.</i>
<i>所有人最终</i></TRANSLATE_16]
<i>都会忘记你。</i></TRANSLATE_17]
[fireworks whistling
and popping]
[烟花呼啸</TRANSLATE_18]
并爆响]</TRANSLATE_19]
<i>Except people
who really love you.</i>
真正爱你的人。</i>
[fireworks continue popping]
[烟花继续噼啪作响]
<i>I couldn’t get to
the people who love me now
without hurting them.</i>
<i>I couldn’t get to
the people who love me now
而不伤害他们。</i>
<i>The only place
I might ever see them again
was somewhere else</i>
<i>The only place
I might ever see them again
是在别处</i>
<i>and some other time.</i>
<i>在另一个时间。</i>
<i>The first step was
getting out of here...</i>
[pliers click]
<i>The first step was
先离开这里...</i>
[钳子咔哒声]
<i>...to get there.</i>
<i>...才能到达那里。</i>
[phone line ringing]
[电话线路接通声]
[Michelle]
<i>Hello?</i>
[米歇尔]
<i>喂？</i>
Hi. Um...
你好。呃...
Wh-- Is, uh--
May I, may I speak to Steve?
请--请问，呃--
我可以，可以找史蒂夫听电话吗？
Please?
Sorry, who is this?
可以吗？
抱歉，请问你是哪位？
<i>Oh, this is a friend.</i>
<i>哦，我是他的朋友。</i>
<i>Well, I mean, this is...
Oliver. His, uh, his cousin.</i>
<i>嗯，我的意思是，我是...</i>
奥利弗。他的，呃，他的表弟。</i>
[chuckles] <i>I was--
I’m doing this little...</i>
[轻笑] <i>我正——</i>
<i>我正在进行一次小小的...</i>
little cross-country trip,
and, uh,
横跨全国的旅行，
然后，呃，
he was, he was expecting me.
I was supposed to visit.
他，他应该是在等我的。
我本来说好要来的。
Mm. Mm.
嗯。嗯。
He didn’t say anything
about a visit.
他没提过
有人要来拜访。
And I didn’t know
he had a cousin.
而且我不知道
他还有个表弟。
He must have forgot
to mention it, I guess.
他大概是忘了
提这件事吧，我猜。
Um... [stammers]
呃... [结巴]
Who am I sp--
who am I speaking with?
我在和——
我是在和谁通话？
<i>Oh, I’m his girlfriend.</i>
<i>哦，我是他女朋友。</i>
What is this about, though?
不过，这是有什么事吗？
’Cause I’m in the middle
of something, so, uh...
因为我手头
正有点事，所以，呃...
<i>His girl-- okay, great.</i>
<i>他的女——好的，知道了。</i>
<i>Could I talk to Steve now?</i>
<i>我现在能和史蒂夫说话吗？</i>
<i>He isn’t here.</i>
<i>他不在这里。</i>
Okay, well,
should I call back
in, like, a...
好的，那么，
我是不是应该
大约...
like, an hour or so?
大约一小时后再打来？
Uh, well, he’s not gonna be
back until December 1st.
呃，那个，他要到
12月1号才会回来。
<i>Where does anyone go
till December?</i>
<i>有谁会去什么地方
待到12月？</i>
<i>He’s in Afghanistan.</i>
<i>他在阿富汗。</i>
He’s not in Afghanistan.
他不在阿富汗。
<i>We got back two years ago
from Afghanistan.</i>
<i>我们两年前
就从阿富汗回来了。</i>
Well, he took
a six-month contract.
嗯，他接了个
六个月的合同工作。
Um, but he asked me
to take messages for him.
呃，不过他让我
帮他记录留言。
<i>Is there something
that you want me</i>
<i>有没有什么
事是你想让我
<i>to tell him if he calls?</i>
<i>在他来电时转告的？</i>
Yeah, uh...
是的，呃...
tell him that, uh,
Cousin Oliver is gonna stay
告诉他，那个，
奥利弗表弟会暂时
with relatives in the area
until he’s back
住在这边的亲戚家
直到他回来，
<i>on December 1st
for a really
important meeting.</i>
<i>在12月1号
参加一个
非常重要的会议。</i>
Okay, I will tell him that.
好的，我会转告他的。
And, uh, I will see you then,
too, I guess.
还有，呃，我想到时候
我也会见到你的。
Cousin Oliver.
奥利弗表弟。
[laughs] <i>Bye.</i>
[line clicks]
[笑] <i>再见。</i>
[电话咔哒声]
[dial tone drones]
[拨号音持续响]
[line ringing]
[电话铃声]
[Becky over phone]
<i>Hello?</i>
[贝基接电话]
<i>喂？</i>
Stop tickling me. Just a sec.
别挠我痒痒了。等一下。
Hello? [giggles]
喂？[咯咯笑]
[giggling]
<i>Gary is crazy.</i>
[咯咯笑]
<i>加里疯了。</i>
<i>Gary!</i>
<i>加里！</i>
[Gary laughing]
<i>Who is it? Hello?</i>
[加里大笑]
<i>是谁啊？喂？</i>
[Gary laughing]
[giggling] Gary!
[加里大笑]
[咯咯笑] 加里！
- Hello?
- Gary.
- 喂？
- 加里。
<i>Who is this?</i>
[Becky continues giggling]
<i>你是谁？</i>
[贝基继续咯咯笑]
<i>Jeff, is this you?</i>
<i>杰夫，是你吗？</i>
<i>If you call here again,
I’m gonna call the cops.</i>
<i>如果你再打过来，
我会报警的。</i>
<i>Do you hear me?</i>
[Jeffrey crying softly]
<i>听见了吗？</i>
[杰弗里轻声哭泣]
<i>We’ve moved on.</i>
<i>我们已经翻篇了。</i>
<i>And you need
to move on, too.
[Becky chattering]</i>
<i>你也需要</i>
继续自己的生活。</i>
[贝基喋喋不休]</i>
<i>Don’t call here anymore.</i>
<i>别再打电话来了。</i>
[line clicks]
[dial tone drones]
[电话咔嗒声]
[拨号音持续响起]
[panting softly]
[轻声喘息]
[sighs]
[叹气]
[clattering]
[哐当声]
[clattering continues]
[哐当声持续]
[Elmo toy laughing]
[艾摩玩具笑声]
[Elmo]
<i>That tickles.</i>
[艾摩]
<i>好痒啊。</i>
[laughing]
[笑声]
<i>Oh, boy, that tickles.</i>
<i>天呐，好痒。</i>
[distorted]
<i>Elmo wants to play.</i>
[失真音效]
<i>艾摩想玩。</i>
[laughing]
[笑]
<i>Let’s play.</i>
[overlapping chatter]
<i>一起玩吧。</i>
[重叠的说话声]
[Elmo 2]
<i>Oh, boy, that tickles.</i>
[艾摩 2]
<i>哦，天哪，好痒。</i>
[Elmo 3]
<i>Elmo love you.</i>
[艾摩 3]
<i>艾摩爱你。</i>
<i>Elmo wants to play.
You’re Elmo’s sweetheart.</i>
<i>艾摩想玩。
你是艾摩的甜心。</i>
<i>That tickles.
Let’s play.</i>
<i>好痒。
一起玩吧。</i>
<i>Elmo love you.</i>
<i>艾摩爱你。</i>
<i>Oh, boy, that tickles.</i>
<i>哦，天哪，好痒。</i>
[distorted,
overlapping chatter]
[失真，
重叠的说话声]
<i>Let’s play.</i>
[Elmo singing "The ABC Song"]
<i>一起玩吧。</i>
[艾摩唱“字母歌”]
<i>Elmo love you.</i>
<i>艾摩爱你。</i>
<i>Elmo loves his ABCs...</i>
<i>艾摩喜欢他的ABC...</i>
[humming]
[哼唱]
[sputters]
[噗嗤声]
Hey, Leigh.
[Mitch]
Otee-Otee-Otis.
Hey, Leigh.
[米奇]
奥蒂-奥蒂-奥蒂斯。
[murmurs]
Hey.
[低语]
嘿。
[Otis]
Hey, Mitch.
[奥蒂斯]
嘿，米奇。
You’re just the man
I want to see.
你正是我
想见的人。
[time clock clicks]
[打卡器咔哒声]
Cool.
酷。
You, uh...
你，呃...
you like Peanut M&Ms, right?
你喜欢花生M&M's，对吧？
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
- 是啊。
- 是吗？
Yeah.
是啊。
[Mitch over headphones]
<i>’Cause we’re missing a lot</i>
[米奇通过耳机]
<i>因为我们少了很多
<i>of Peanut M&Ms.
You have any idea why?</i>
<i>花生M&M巧克力豆。
<i>你知道是怎么回事吗？</i>
<i>No.</i>
<i>不知道。</i>
[Mitch]
<i>What’s wrong?</i>
[Otis] <i>Nothing’s wrong.</i>
[米奇]
<i>怎么了？</i>
[奥蒂斯] <i>没事。</i>
[Mitch]
<i>Seem nervous.</i>
[Otis] <i>I’m not.</i>
[米奇]
<i>你好像很紧张。</i>
[奥蒂斯] <i>我没有。</i>
[Leigh]
<i>No.</i>
[利]
<i>不行。</i>
[Mitch]
No?
No. Not happening.
[米奇]
不行？
不行。没得商量。
You can’t talk to him
like that.
你不能那样
跟他说话。
Okay. You know, we are missing
half a dozen boxes out there.
好吧。你知道，我们那边少了
半打箱子。
And I just thought-- boop--
我刚才就在想——啵——
they got to be hiding
somewhere-- boop.
它们肯定被藏在
某个地方——啵。
[Leigh]
<i>I am so sorry.</i>
[莉]
<i>真是抱歉。</i>
[Mitch]
<i>Oh, God.
He cannot talk to you that way.</i>
[米奇]
<i>哦，天啊。
他不能那样跟你说话。</i>
[Mitch]
<i>I’m the bad guy now.</i>
[米奇]
<i>现在我倒成了坏人。</i>
[Leigh] <i>Hey. You got to
stick up for yourself.</i>
[莉] <i>嘿。你得
为自己出头。</i>
<i>Okay? Or he’s just
gonna get worse.</i>
<i>好吗？不然他只会
变本加厉。</i>
I’m not big
on conflict, so...
我不太擅长
处理冲突，所以...
Yeah.
Okay, well,
we’ll-we’ll work on that.
是啊。
好吧，那么，
我们——我们会改进的。
[Otis]
<i>Cool.</i>
[奥蒂斯]
<i>酷。</i>
[Leigh] <i>Listen, Mitch,
you really hurt
Otis’s feelings,</i>
[莉] <i>听着，米奇，
你确实伤害了
奥蒂斯的感情，
<i>and I think
you should apologize.</i>
而且我认为
你应该道歉。
[Mitch] <i>I’m sorry.</i>
[Jeffrey mumbles]
[米奇] <i>对不起。</i>
[杰弗瑞咕哝着]
[Leigh]
<i>Well, that’s a good start.</i>
[莉]
<i>嗯，这是个好的开始。</i>
[Mitch chuckles] <i>Okay.</i>
[Leigh] <i>You know,</i>
[米奇轻笑] <i>好吧。</i>
[莉] <i>你知道，</i>
<i>people respect kindness
in a leader.</i>
<i>人们敬重领导者的
仁慈。</i>
[Mitch] <i>Mm.</i>
[米奇] <i>嗯。</i>
[Leigh]
<i>W-With that in mind,</i>
[莉]
<i>那-那么考虑到这点，</i>
<i>I wanted to invite you
to my church.</i>
<i>我想邀请你
来我的教堂。</i>
<i>Crossroads Church.</i>
<i>十字路口教堂。</i>
It’s, uh, just across
the interstate.
它，呃，就在州际公路
对面。
Uh... Have you been?
呃...你去过吗？
Not very churchy.
不太信教。
Okay, well, I’m in charge
of the toy drive there,
好吧，其实我在那里
负责玩具募捐活动
and it got me thinking,
here I am,
这让我想到
我在这里
working in a toy store
of all places,
偏偏在玩具店工作
（强调语气）
and you haven’t even donated
one toy to my toy drive.
你却连一件玩具
都没捐给我的募捐活动
Well, we sell toys here.
We don’t give ’em away.
我们这儿是卖玩具的
不白送
Okay. What about
all those returned toys?
好吧 那
那些退货的玩具呢？
Perfectly good ones
that we can’t sell.
明明完好无损
又不能卖
We run a business here,
Leigh.
我们这是在做生意
莉
Okay.
Well, you can still come.
好吧
不过你还是可以来
You know,
all people are welcome.
你知道，
所有人都欢迎来。
<i>Even if they’re mean
or aren’t quite ready yet.</i>
<i>即使他们不友善
或者还没完全准备好。</i>
<i>So you can come, bring
a big bag of toys, or not.</i>
<i>所以你可以来，带
一大袋玩具，或者不带。</i>
[Jeffrey chuckles]
<i>You’ll be welcome.</i>
[杰弗瑞轻笑]
<i>你会受到欢迎的。</i>
<i>But bring the toys and you
could be a good guy for once.</i>
<i>但带上玩具的话，你
说不定能当回好人。</i>
<i>Don’t you want to be
a good guy?</i>
<i>你难道不想
当个好人吗？</i>
<i>Come on, Mitch! Be a good guy!</i>
<i>来吧米奇！当个好人！</i>
[Mitch]
<i>Okay.</i>
[米奇]
<i>好吧。</i>
[sighs]
[叹气]
[mutters]
[低声嘟囔]
Is that garbage?
那是垃圾吗？
Uh...
呃...
Huh?
Do you want me to put that
in the garbage for you?
嗯？
你要我帮你把这个
扔进垃圾桶吗？
It’s just toys for the...
这只是些玩具...
Uh, I heard
there was a toy drive.
呃，我听说
有个玩具捐赠活动。
Well, it’s right
this way.
嗯，就在
这边。
It’s o-- I’ll just
leave ’em here. It’s okay.
没关——我就
放这儿吧。没关系。
[chuckles]
I’m not gonna walk
[轻笑]
我可不想
all the way down there
in these heels.
穿着这双高跟鞋
走那么远。
It’s very nice
of you.
你真是
太好了。
Here you go.
给你。
Thank you.
谢谢。
[laughs]
Oh, it’s too heavy
for me.
[笑]
哦，这对我来说
太重了。
[chuckles]
Got to bring it on
in there.
[轻笑]
得把它搬进去
那里。
Come on, I’ll show you
where the toys go.
来吧，我带你去
看看玩具放哪里。
Where do you want me
to put ’em?
你想让我放
哪儿？
You can bring ’em
right in here.
你可以把它们搬
到这里面来。
Service
is about to begin.
礼拜
马上就要开始了。
[light gospel music
playing inside]
[轻柔的福音音乐
在室内播放]
[Pastor Ron]
Anyone that feels
alone out there...
[罗恩牧师]
任何感到
孤独的人...
[music continues]
[音乐继续]
...just come on down here.
...就请到前面来。
[speaking quietly]
[轻声说道]
’Cause you belong here.
因为你属于这里。
We’re all sinners here,
我们都是有罪之人，
which is why I ask my wife
sometimes to sing this tune.
所以我有时会请我妻子
唱这首歌。
<i>♪ In times of despair ♪</i>
<i>♪ 在绝望的时刻 ♪</i>
<i>♪ I think about
The good things
That you’ve done ♪</i>
<i>♪ 我想起
那些美好的事
你曾做过 ♪</i>
[congregation whooping
and murmuring]
[会众欢呼
低语]
<i>♪ Ooh, and though
You’re not there ♪</i>
不在那里 ♪</i>
<i>♪ I sometimes ask myself ♪</i>
<i>♪ 我有时问自己 ♪</i>
[Pastor Ron]
<i>♪ Is anyone? ♪</i>
[Eileen] <i>♪ Is anyone? ♪</i>
[罗恩牧师]
<i>♪ 是否有人？ ♪</i>
[艾琳] <i>♪ 是否有人？ ♪</i>
<i>♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Oh ♪</i>
<i>♪ 是啊 ♪
♪ 哦 ♪</i>
[choir joins in]
<i>♪ It’s so hard being human ♪</i>
[合唱团加入]
<i>♪ 做人如此艰难 ♪</i>
<i>♪ With all the troubles ♪</i>
<i>♪ 面对所有烦恼 ♪</i>
<i>♪ In sight ♪</i>
<i>♪ 映入眼帘 ♪</i>
<i>♪ But somehow I know ♪</i>
<i>♪ 但我冥冥中知道 ♪</i>
<i>♪ I know, I know,
I know, I know ♪</i>
<i>♪ 我知道，我知道，
我知道，我知道 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Everything’s gonna
Work out all right ♪</i>
<i>♪ 一切都会
好起来的 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Hey, yeah ♪</i>
<i>♪ 嘿，耶 ♪</i>
<i>♪ But somehow I know ♪</i>
<i>♪ 但我冥冥中知道 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Everything’s gonna
Work out all right ♪</i>
<i>♪ 一切都会
好起来的 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Hey, but somehow I know ♪</i>
<i>♪ 嘿，但我冥冥中知道 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Everything’s gonna
Work out all right ♪</i>
<i>♪ 一切都会
好起来的 ♪</i>
[song ends]
[cheering and applauding]
[歌曲结束]
[欢呼与掌声]
[Eileen]
Hallelujah.
[艾琳]
哈利路亚。
[lively chatter]
[热烈的交谈声]
Wow. Somebody is
very hungry, huh?
哇。有人
饿坏了，是吧？
Big appetite there, huh?
胃口不错嘛，嗯？
[mouth full] Sorry.
[laughs] Please.
[嘴里塞满食物] 抱歉。
[笑] 请便。
I haven’t had food this good
in so long. [chuckles]
我好久没吃到
这么美味的东西了。[轻笑]
No, that’s great.
Big food for a big guy.
不，这很棒。
大块头就该吃大餐。
- Yeah.
- 是啊。
- 没错。
Now, you can’t sneak
out of here
你可不能
偷偷溜走
without saying hello
to the pastor and his wife.
而不跟牧师
和他的夫人打声招呼。
No.
It’s against the rules.
不行。
这违反规定。
No, I would never.
I would never.
不，我绝不会的。
我绝不会那样。
I’m Eileen.
我是艾琳。
John. Z-- uh, Zorin.
John Zorin.
约翰·佐——呃，佐林。
约翰·佐林。
Yeah, I haven’t seen you
around the area before.
是的，我之前没在这儿见过你
在这一带。
I noticed you,
obviously, in the,
in the-the row there.
我注意到你了，
很明显，在，
在，在那排座位上。
Where are you from?
You new to the area?
你从哪里来？
你是新搬来的吗？
Yeah, uh, I’m-I’m...
是的，呃，我是——我是……
[sighs] I’m just new
to this place
and, really, everything.
[叹气] 我只是刚来
这个地方
而且，真的，所有一切都很陌生。
You know, it’s, um...
你知道，就是，嗯……
All of this is
really just, you know...
所有这一切
真的只是，你知道……
Every-Everything here
is just new for me.
每——这里的每件事
对我来说都是全新的。
I’m-I’m down
from New York City.
我是——我是从
纽约市来的。
That’s
a walking man’s town,
那可是
一个适合步行者的城市，
I mean, if ever
I’ve been-been to one.
我是说，如果真有
那么一个地方的话。
That is
a walking man’s town.
That is correct.
那就是
一个适合步行者的城市。
没错。
I bet you go through a lot
of pair of sneakers, don’t you?
我猜你肯定穿坏了不少
运动鞋吧？
[laughs] Everyone does.
Right? Do you go through...
[笑] 大家都这样。
对吧？你是不是也穿坏...
Yeah, yeah.
Oh, my. You’ve--
是啊，是啊。
哦，天哪。你居然——
You got very small feet
for a big guy.
你这双脚可真小
对于你这个大个子来说。
No, I actually have
large feet. It’s just,
不，其实我的脚
很大。只是，
I put on the wrong shoes,
and I don’t know,
我穿错了鞋子，
而且我也不知道，
I think these are, like,
nines in women’s.
我觉得这双大概是
女码九号。
And I’m sorry, I would never
wear sneakers to church.
抱歉，我绝不会
穿运动鞋去教堂。
I-I’m really sorry.
我--我真的很抱歉。
You know, I-I would like
to introduce you to someone.
你知道，我--我想
给你介绍一个人。
I’d like to introduce you
to Leigh Wainscott.
我想向你介绍
一下Leigh Wainscott。
She runs the toy drive here,
她负责这里的玩具募捐活动，
and I heard you gave
such a generous donation.
我听说你捐了
一笔非常慷慨的款项。
I know she’d like
to thank you for it.
我知道她一定
想为此感谢你。
You know, she looks a bit busy
over there, actually, Eileen.
你知道，她看起来有点忙
在那边，说真的，Eileen。
She’s having a serious
conversation with her daughter.
她正在和她女儿
进行严肃的谈话。
[chatter fades]
[聊天声渐弱]
Now?
现在？
[Pastor Ron]
Yeah.
[Eileen] We can.
[Ron牧师]
是的。
[Eileen] 我们可以的。
Yeah. Okay.
You made such
a great donation.
好的。嗯。
你做出了如此
巨大的贡献。
Okay. Yeah, sure.
Yeah. Hey, hey.
好的。嗯，当然。
嗯。嘿，嘿。
Okay, great.
Uh, Leigh. Hey, Leigh.
好的，太棒了。
呃，莉。嘿，莉。
Leigh. Hey, Leigh.
莉。嘿，莉。
Come, come say hi
to our mystery man.
来，过来打个招呼
见见我们的神秘先生。
Okay.
Come on.
好的。
来吧。
Yeah.
嗯。
是啊。
This is our all-star Leigh.
这是我们全能的莉。
She is the backbone
of everything
她是一切
美好事务
that is good going on
in this church.
得以顺利进行的
中坚力量。
She does the outreach,
does the meals,
她负责外联，
负责餐食，
does the toy drive,
she...
负责玩具募捐，
她...
I really don’t know how
she does it all, but she does.
我真不知道
她是怎么做到的，但她确实做到了。
And this is John...
这位是约翰...
Zorin? Zorin from New York.
佐林？纽约来的佐林。
Oh, New York.
哦，纽约。
That’s far from here.
Yeah, a little bit, yeah.
离这儿可远了。
是啊，有点远，没错。
[Eileen] So, John-- he made
a very generous toy donation.
[艾琳] 所以，约翰——他捐赠了
一大批玩具，非常慷慨。
Oh, that’s so kind
of you. We...
哦，你真是
太客气了。我们...
Couldn’t have come
at a better time.
来得
正是时候。
No, I-I mean, um,
I really like Christmas
and-and birthdays,
不，我-我是说，嗯，
我真的很喜欢圣诞节
和-和生日，
uh, and just
gift-giving time.
呃，就是
送礼物的时节。
[laughs]
I mean, I don’t know.
[笑]
我是说，我也不知道。
[stammers]
I just love kids.
You have kids, John?
[口吃]
我就是喜欢孩子。
你有孩子吗，约翰？
Well...
You have a family,
or are you single?
嗯…
你成家了，
还是单身？
I’m, uh, just officially
divorced, that’s all.
我，呃，只是刚
正式离婚了，仅此而已。
[Pastor Ron]
Oh, I’m sorry, John.
[罗恩牧师]
哦，我很抱歉，约翰。
Not-not all marriages
work out, right?
不-不是所有的婚姻
都能圆满，对吧？
That’s-- that is true.
那-那倒是真的。
But to answer your question,
I do have kids.
不过回答你的问题，
我确实有孩子。
I have two little
monster boys,
我有两个小
捣蛋鬼儿子，
and I got a little girl
that is my best pal.
我还有个女儿
她是我最好的伙伴
That’s sweet.
And, um... Yeah.
真温馨
嗯...是的
But they’re in New York,
and I’m here working.
但他们都在纽约
而我在这里工作
And what-what-what do you--
what do you do for work?
那-那-那你--
你是做什么工作的？
Well, I... [sighs]
I-I work for the government,
这个... [叹气]
我-我为政府工作
um, but I can’t exactly
talk about it.
但我不太方便
具体说明
It’s, uh, it’s classified
这属于
and all that silliness.
[Eileen] Oh.
机密之类的无聊规定
[艾琳] 哦
Well, John Zorin from New York,
our New York spy.
纽约来的约翰·佐林
我们的纽约间谍
No! No, no.
[laughter]
不！不不
[笑声]
Definitely not that.
I like that.
绝对不是那样
我喜欢这个。
Okay, okay.
好的，好的。
Well, can I ask you,
can we count on you
to join us next Sunday?
那么，我能问你，
我们能指望你
下周日加入我们吗？
Yeah.
Well, and also
this Wednesday.
是的。
嗯，还有
这周三。
Oh. Wow. Yeah.
What’s-what’s Wednesday?
哦。哇。好啊。
周三是-是什么事？
Uh, I run a singles dinner,
呃，我组织了一个单身人士晚餐会，
and this week’s gonna be
at a Red Lobster.
这周的晚餐会
在一家红龙虾餐厅。
I love a Red Lobster.
我爱红龙虾餐厅。
I mean,
not just the seafood.
Those cheese biscuits...
我是说，
不只是因为海鲜。
那些芝士小饼干...
Mm-hmm.
I mean, yeah.
嗯哼。
我是说，当然。
I-I mean,
are you gonna be there?
我-我是说，
你会来吗？
[Eileen]
Hmm. Leigh?
[艾琳]
嗯。莉？
You think you’re gonna join us
for our first single dinner?
你觉得你会参加
我们的首次单身晚餐吗？
Well, I never thought of myself
as being a single,
嗯，我从未想过自己
会是单身，
but, sure, yeah,
I-I’ll-I’ll go.
不过，当然，是的，
我-我会-我会去的。
[Eileen] Okay.
Yeah, I’ll-I’ll be there.
[艾琳] 好的。
是的，我-我会去的。
Count me in.
[Eileen] Okay.
算我一个。
[艾琳] 好的。
[Kami] Good to see you.
Thank you so much.
[卡米] 很高兴见到你。
非常感谢。
Thank you for joining us today.
Really appreciate it.
感谢你今天加入我们。
真的很感激。
[Jeffrey]
<i>I liked being John</i>
[杰弗里]
<i>比起喜欢杰夫，</i>
<i>better than I liked
being Jeff.</i>
<i>我更喜欢做约翰</i>
胜过当杰夫。</
See you on Wednesday.
Wednesday. Yes, ma’am.
周三见。
周三。好的，女士。
<i>John was a good guy.</i>
约翰是个好人。
<i>People liked him.</i>
大家都喜欢他。
<i>Leigh seemed to
like him, too.</i>
莉似乎也
对他有好感。
<i>But there was no way
a girl like her
was gonna really fall</i>
但像她这样的女孩
绝不可能
真的爱上
<i>for a guy
in women’s running shoes
and a Spider-Man T-shirt.</i>
一个穿着
女式跑鞋
和蜘蛛侠T恤的男人。
[groans]
[呻吟]
<i>Also, I really needed
to see a dentist.</i>
另外，我真的需要
去看牙医了。
<i>Living on candy is
hard on your teeth.</i>
靠糖果度日
对牙齿很不好。
[entry bell jingles]
[门铃叮当声]
Good afternoon.
How are you?
下午好。
你好吗？
Good, sir.
How are you?
很好，先生。
您怎么样？
[bag unzips]
See what you give me
for these.
[拉开包链声]
看看这些
你能给我什么价
Uh, how about
ten apiece? 300.
呃，每件
十块怎么样？总共三百。
Yeah, I’ll go 300.
好的，就三百吧。
Okay, let’s do that.
Yeah, deal. Yes, sir.
行，就这么定了。
好的，成交。是的，先生。
M.O.D. on number 29.
29号有中度龋坏。
14 cavities. That’s a lot
of cavities for an adult.
14个蛀牙。这蛀牙
对成年人来说可不少。
Yeah, I’m sorry.
是的，很抱歉。
I just have a bit--
我只是有点——
naturally, I guess,
a bit of a sweet tooth,
我想，大概是天生
就有点爱吃甜食，
and I’ve had access
to a lot of really good candy.
而且我最近能接触到
很多非常好的糖果。
Just haven’t been able to...
Open your mouth
就是一直没能...
张开嘴
wide, please.
...s-stop. Okay.
张大点，谢谢。
...停-停下。好的。
[whirring]
[嗡嗡声]
[laughter, lively chatter]
[pop music playing]
[笑声，活跃的交谈声]
[流行音乐播放中]
Look at those.
看看这些。
Oh, wow. [chuckles]
哦，哇。[轻笑]
[Kami chuckles]
[excited chatter, clapping]
[卡米轻笑]
[兴奋的交谈声，鼓掌]
[Jeffrey]
Hello. [chuckles]
[杰弗里]
你好。[轻笑]
Hello, ladies.
[women] Hi!
女士们好。
[女人们] 嗨！
Hi.
你好。
How is everyone?
[chuckles]
Good.
大家都好吗？
[轻笑]
很好。
Oh, okay.
[women chuckling]
哦，好的。
[女士们轻笑]
I thought this was
a singles brunch,
我原以为这是
一个单身人士的早午餐，
not a supermodel brunch.
而不是超模早午餐。
[laughter]
Ooh. [laughs]
[笑声]
哦。[笑]
[Kami] You could always
squeeze in down here by us.
[卡米] 你可以
挤到我们这边来坐。
[laughter]
[笑声]
Well, we wanted
to welcome you, John.
嗯，我们想
欢迎你，约翰。
[Kami] Yes.
Welcome, welcome.
[卡米] 是的。
欢迎，欢迎。
Am I the only guy
that’s gonna be here today?
我是今天这里
唯一的男士吗？
[laughs]
[笑]
[women] Yes.
Uh-huh. Yep. You are.
[女士们] 是的。
嗯哼。是的。你是。
Turns out to be so, yes.
Right. Okay.
看来确实如此，是的。
好的。明白了。
Yes. I hope we’re not
overwhelming for you.
是的。希望我们不会
让你感到不知所措。
Oh, no, no, no,
I’m actually-- I-I’m
liking it very much.
哦，不，不，不，
其实我——我我
非常喜欢这样。
Okay, good.
I love having
so many new friends,
好的，很好。
我很高兴能有
这么多新朋友，
especially beautiful friends.
Um...
尤其是漂亮的朋友。
嗯...
Ooh.
[woman]
Sweet one.
哦。
[女人]
嘴真甜。
So, John, I understand
you work for the government.
What kind of work?
那么，约翰，我了解到
你为政府工作。
具体是做什么的呢？
I-I would love
to get into those details,
but I’m undercover, so, um...
我——我很想
透露细节，
但我在执行秘密任务，所以，嗯...
[women oohing]
Oh, that sounds mysterious.
[女人们发出赞叹声]
哦，听起来很神秘啊。
No, I can promise
it’s not that mysterious.
不，我可以保证
没那么神秘。
It’s really quite boring.
[chuckles]
其实挺无聊的。
[轻笑]
I never knew there was
an intelligence unit
here in Charlotte.
我从不知道
夏洛特市有个
情报部门。
Oh, are you law enforcement?
哦，你是执法人员吗？
I’m retired now,
but I was.
我现在退休了，
但曾经是。
Wow. That’s amazing.
哇，太厉害了。
[high-pitched gasp]
[高声吸气]
Am I, am I, uh...
[laughter]
我是不是，我是不是，呃...
[笑声]
Am I arrested?
How does this work?
我被逮捕了吗？
这是怎么回事？
I don’t want to
make you upset.
我不想
惹你生气。
[Kami]
You’re embarrassing
everyone, Sally.
[神明]
你让大家
都很难堪，莎莉。
He did not come here
to be interrogated.
他不是来这儿
接受审问的。
No, no, no,
I actually really like it.
不，不，不，
我其实挺喜欢的。
I feel a lot safer
with her here.
有她在这里
我感觉安全多了。
Um, but-but yeah.
嗯，不过——是的。
Um, there’s intelligence
just about in every major city.
嗯，情报机构
几乎遍布每个主要城市。
We just don’t advertise
that much, yeah.
我们只是不怎么
大肆宣传，是的。
Well, if he’s undercover,
why’s he at a singles dinner
at Red Lobster?
好吧，如果他是卧底，
为什么他会出现在红龙虾餐厅
的单身晚宴上？
[overlapping chatter]
That’s a fair question.
[重叠的聊天声]
这问题提得合理。
Well...
嗯...
That’s a fair question.
I-I can...
这是个好问题。
我-我可以...
That is, that is a question
that is not classified.
也就是说，这个问题
不属于机密。
I am here possibly looking
for the next Ms. John Zorin.
我在这里可能是想寻找
下一位佐林太太。
[laughter, applause]
[笑声，掌声]
Oh, please. Oh, please.
[Jeffrey stammers]
哦，拜托。哦，拜托。
[杰弗瑞结结巴巴地说]
See, but there-there
is a problem, though.
你看，但-但是
有个问题。
I’m having a bit of an issue
that there’s just
too many beautiful choices here
我有点困扰
因为这里
有太多漂亮的选择
to choose from.
[excited chatter]
可供挑选。
[兴奋的交谈声]
No, I’m-I’m sorry.
I should not have said that.
不，我-我很抱歉。
我不该那么说的。
My mom always told me
do not compliment a woman
我妈妈总是告诉我
不要赞美女性的美貌
on her beauty because
it makes her self-conscious.
夸赞她的美貌，因为
这会让她不自在。
Um, always start
with their shoes.
嗯，应该总是从
她们的鞋子开始夸起。
[laughter]
[笑声]
Speaking of.
Hold on a second.
说到这个。
等一下。
Let me get
under this table.
[laughter]
让我
钻到桌子底下去看看。
[笑声]
Excuse me.
失礼了。
Got some high boots
down there.
下面有双高筒靴
呢。
Stilettos at brunch.
All right, girl.
早午餐穿细高跟。
可以啊，姐妹。
[laughter continues]
Okay, okay.
[笑声持续]
好了，好了。
[Kami]
It is getting hot in here.
[卡米]
这儿开始热起来了。
[lively chatter]
No, no, no, no.
[活跃的交谈声]
不，不，不，不。
[Leigh]
<i>That was really fun.</i>
<i>刚才真的很有趣。</i>
Look, I don’t get out much,
so this was fun for me.
你看，我不太经常出门，
所以这对我来说很有趣。
Me neither.
我也是。
[chuckles]
You sure made their day.
[轻笑]
你确实让她们很开心。
They made my day, truly.
是她们让我很开心，真的。
This is my car.
I mean, I’ve never been...
这是我的车。
我是说，我从来没有...
- This is you? Ooh, a Subaru.
- Yeah.
- 这是你的车？哦，斯巴鲁。
- 是的。
Yeah.
是的。
I like it.
我喜欢它。
All right,
I’m-I’m getting
my courage up.
好吧，
我-我正在
鼓起勇气。
Um...
嗯...
I have two questions
to ask you.
我有两个问题
问你。
Two? Just two?
两个？就两个？
Yeah.
All right.
Let’s hear it.
对。
好吧。
说来听听。
Drumroll. Give me
the first one. Go.
请准备。给我
第一个问题。说吧。
Um, you’re gay, right?
嗯，你是同性恋，对吧？
What? I’m what?
You’re gay.
什么？我是什么？
你是同性恋。
- Gay? No.
- Yeah.
- 同性恋？不。
- 是啊。
[laughs]
What?
[笑]
什么？
Are you kidding
right now?
No, I...
你是在开玩笑
吗？
不，我...
No, I mean, look,
I don’t have
anything against gays.
不，我是说，听着，
我并没有
反对同性恋。
I love gays,
but, like, I’m--
no, absolutely not.
我挺喜欢同性恋者的，
但是，怎么说，我——
不，绝对不是。
You just...
What made you think
I was gay?
你只是...
是什么让你觉得
我是同性恋？
You just seem like
one of the girls.
你只是看起来
像是姐妹淘的一员。
Or, like, you seem
to love women’s shoes.
或者说，你看起来
好像很爱女鞋。
No, that’s not
what that was.
[laughs]
不，不是
那么回事。
[笑]
All right.
Uh-uh.
好吧。
呃-呃。
All right, well, that--
if that’s a no,
好吧，那么，既然——
如果答案是否定的，
we can go straight
to question two.
我们可以直接
进入第二个问题。
Okay. Uh, yeah.
I guess, hit me.
好的。呃，是的。
那么，请问吧。
[chuckles]
Um...
[轻笑]
嗯...
Um, would you like
to go out with me?
你愿意
和我约会吗？
On a date?
就是那种约会？
Okay.
好吧。
Wow, you’re
a very forward person.
哇，你真是
个很直接的人。
I, uh...
我，呃...
Um, yes, I would,
I would very much--
really, very much--
嗯，是的，我愿意，
我非常——
真的，非常——
like to go out
on a date with you.
想和你
出去约会。
[laughs]
I don’t know, yes.
[笑]
我也不知道怎么说，愿意。
Yes is the answer
to that.
答案是愿意
就是这个答案。
All right.
Okay.
好的。
I’m free, um,
next Saturday morning?
我有空，嗯，
下周六早上？
Perfect.
完美。
I’ll pick you up.
Where do you live?
我来接你。
你住在哪里？
[sputters]
I live in
a really boring, uh,
[支支吾吾]
我住在
一个非常无聊的，呃，
government building
that’s non-disclosed
to the public.
政府大楼里
那个地址是
不对外公开的。
How about this?
这样如何？
Uh, let’s meet
at Freedom Park.
呃，我们
在自由公园见面吧。
Saturday morning,
8:00 a.m.
周六早上，
早上8点。
Sounds like a,
like a-- uh, well,
sounds like a date.
听起来像个，
像个——呃，好吧，
听起来像是个约会。
It’s a date.
So it’s a date.
就这么说定了。
那就约好了。
Okay. Bye.
好的。再见。
好的。拜拜。
All right. All right. Sorry.
Hey. [laughs]
好吧好吧。对不起。
嘿。[笑]
You were shaking,
and I was going...
你当时在发抖，
而我就想...
But don’t get...
There’s a car.
[gasps] Oh, shit.
但别太...
有辆车。
[倒吸一口气] 哦，该死。
[laughs] Okay.
All right. Yep.
[笑] 好吧。
好的。是的。
All right,
that was awkward.
Okay.
好吧，
刚才真尴尬。
好的。
See ya.
Bye!
再见。
拜拜！
[Leigh]
It’s hot.
[莉]
天真热。
[Jeffrey]
It’s hot. [grunts]
[杰弗里]
天气真热。[咕哝声]
Wow.
哇哦。
You’re in
really good shape.
你的
身材真不错。
Thanks, girl.
谢啦，姐妹。
[both laugh]
[两人都笑了]
My ex, Jeffrey, he...
Yeah?
我的前任杰弗里，他...
嗯？
What?
You said Jeffrey.
怎么了？
你刚才说了杰弗里。
Yeah. That’s my ex’s name--
Jeffrey.
是啊。那是我前任的名字——
杰弗里。
Got it, right.
Yeah.
明白了，对。
嗯。
His name
was Jeffrey?
他的名字
是杰弗里？
Yeah. He was in...
Wow.
对。他的身材...
天哪。
...horrible shape.
...简直糟透了。
Like, we had no...
比如，我们当时没有...
No...?
It’s just been
a long time.
没有...？
只是已经
过去很久了。
Oh, okay.
But we’re nothing alike.
哦，好吧。
但我们一点都不像。
Good to know.
Yeah, I-I like people.
那就好。
是啊，我-我喜欢和人打交道。
He didn’t talk.
他不怎么说话。
He just read war history novels
on the toilet.
他只是在马桶上
读战争历史小说。
[laughs]
What?
[笑]
怎么了？
Mm-hmm.
[gags]
嗯哼。
[干呕]
N-No, Jeffrey,
that is gross.
[laughs]
不-不是吧，杰弗里，
这太恶心了。
[笑]
Right? [laughs]
[gags]
是吧？[笑]
[干呕]
He loves his books,
but when it comes to
time for the girls
他喜欢他的书，
但涉及到
陪女儿们的时候
or homework
or driving lessons,
just doesn’t show up.
或者辅导作业
或是驾驶课，
他就不见人影。
Stressful.
压力山大。
I just think you need
a little bit more fun
in your life,
我只是觉得你需要
在生活中
多点儿乐趣，
to be honest.
[stammers]
说实话。
[口吃]
Okay.
好吧。
Do you want to go
back to mine and have
some fun right now?
你想不想
去我那儿
现在找点乐子？
What?
什么？
Really?
Mm-hmm.
真的吗？
嗯哼。
Yes. Very much, yes.
是的。非常想，是的。
I would very much--
yeah, mm-hmm.
我非常想——
嗯，是的。
Okay.
Mm-hmm. Yeah. Now?
好的。
嗯。是的。现在？
Yeah.
All right.
对。
好吧。
Told you I wasn’t gay.
早说过我不是同性恋。
[laughing]
[笑]
Shut up.
[laughing]
闭嘴。
[笑]
[Jeffrey]
Tell me about your daughters.
[杰弗里]
跟我说说你的女儿们。
[Leigh] Their names
are Dee and Lindsay.
[莉] 她们的名字
是迪伊和林赛。
Dee’s 11.
迪伊11岁。
She’s pretty sensitive
and creative.
她比较敏感
且有创造力。
She’s like...
I don’t know.
她就像...
我也不知道。
She-she hasn’t let me
cut her hair
since she was a baby.
她-她从
剪她的头发
从她还是个婴儿起就不让
She’s one of those kids.
她就是那种孩子
And then Lindsay’s 16.
林赛今年16岁
She has a sign
on her door that says,
她房门上贴了个牌子
上面写着
"Emotionally unavailable."
"情感隔离中"
[laughs softly]
She also just
got her learner’s permit
[轻声笑]
她还刚刚
拿到了学习驾照
but refuses to drive,
even though
she wants her freedom,
但拒绝开车
尽管
她渴望自由
so that’s where we’re at.
Oh, is that right? [laughs]
所以我们现状就是这样
哦，是吗？[笑]
Well, I’m a good driver.
我车技不错
If you want me to teach her,
I-I’ll happily do it.
如果你想让我教她
我-我很乐意帮忙
[laughs]
We just met.
[笑]
我们才刚认识
That’s a good point.
That’s a... [stammers]
说得有道理。
那是... [结巴]
Yeah, I know.
嗯，我知道。
Um, I just love kids, so...
呃，我就是很喜欢孩子，所以...
Okay, well, maybe...
maybe you could
meet ’em sometime.
好吧，也许...
也许你可以
找个时间见见他们。
You know, like, maybe
you could come over for...
你知道的，比如，也许
你可以过来...
for pizza one weekend, maybe?
找个周末吃披萨，怎么样？
Like a pizza party?
Can we have a pizza party?
像个披萨派对？
我们能办个披萨派对吗？
Like a pizza Saturday?[laughs]
比如披萨星期六？[笑]
I haven’t been
out of the house,
我已经很久
没出过门了，
let alone on a date, okay?
Okay.
更别说约会了，好吗？
好吧。
In a very long time.
Mm-hmm.
很长时间了。
嗯哼。
Um, I... I don’t know
if my girls are ready
for, you know,
呃，我... 我不知道
不知道我的女儿们是否准备好了
面对，就是
M-Mom to be dating
just yet.
妈妈要去约会这件事
至少现在还没准备好。
I get that.
我理解。
We can still have a pizza party
and just make it
我们仍然可以办个披萨派对
就让它
just totally normal.
显得完全正常。
I’m just a friend from church,
you know,
我就只是个教会认识的朋友，
你知道，
that happens to be
a government spy.
碰巧是
个政府间谍。
[laughs]
A non-gay one.
[笑]
一个非同性恋的。
You know,
a non-gay government spy
你知道，
一个非同性恋的政府间谍
that just comes over
and wants to, you know,
就是过来
想要，那个，
have pizza with you
and your daughters.
和你
还有你的女儿们一起吃披萨。
- You know, just make it normal.
- Okay.
- 你知道，就让它显得正常点。
- 好的。
You’re-you’re not normal,
John,
你-你并不正常，
约翰，
but...
[snickers]
但是...
[窃笑]
[laughing]
I like you.
[笑]
我喜欢你。
You know what’s not normal?
Hmm?
你知道什么不正常吗？
嗯？
You just look like this
all the time?[scoffs]
你就一直
是这副模样？[嗤笑]
Looking inviting.
[laughing]
看起来挺诱人。
[笑]
[Jeffrey mumbles playfully]
[Leigh squeals, laughs]
[杰弗里顽皮地咕哝]
[莉尖叫，笑]
[birds chirping]
[鸟鸣]
[sighs]
[叹气]
[bags rustling]
[袋子沙沙作响]
[knocking on door]
[Leigh] Oh.
[敲门声]
[Leigh] 哦。
He’s here. Okay?
他来了。可以吗？
[door opens]
[开门声]
[Jeffrey]
Hello.
你好。
Please come in.
请进。
Wow, that’s
a lot of food.
哇，这
食物可真多。
Girls,
this is my friend John.
姑娘们，
这位是我的朋友约翰。
John, these are my girls.
约翰，这是我的女儿们。
Hey, girls.
嘿，姑娘们。
Uh, hi.
I’m-I’m John Zorin.
呃，你好。
我是——我是约翰·佐林。
I’m your mom’s good friend
from church.
我是你们妈妈的好朋友
来自教堂。
You must be Dee.
你一定是迪伊了。
That’s short for Delia?
是迪莉娅的简称吗？
Yeah.
Yes.
对。
是的。
You must be Lindsay,
and that’s short for...
你一定是林赛，
简称是……
That’s not short for anything
at all, actually. [laughs]
这名字没有简称
实际上完全没有。[笑声]
Look, I’ve heard
so much about you guys.
听着，我早就
听说过你们很多事了。
Uh, and one of the things
that I have heard,
呃，其中有件事
我听说的是，
is that you, Dee,
happen to be a huge fan
of <i>Zelda,</i> like I am.
你，迪伊，
正好是个超级粉丝
喜欢《塞尔达》，就像我一样。
Is that true?
是真的吗？
Yeah.
Is that right?
是啊。
是这样吗？
Good, ’cause I got you
this Link doll.
很好，因为我给你
带了这个林克玩偶。
[laughs]
[笑声]
And another question:
还有个问题：
[whispering]
Have you played <i>Four Swords?</i>
[低声说]
你玩过《四支剑》吗？
No.
It is so amazing,
没有。
它真的太棒了，
and it comes with
this special controller
而且它附带
这个特殊控制器
that I’ll teach you
how to use later
我稍后会教你
如何使用
until you can whup my butt,
直到你能打败我，
which you’ll probably be able
to do really quickly
你可能很快
就能做到
‘’cause I hear you’re,
like, a <i>Zelda</i> master.
因为我听说你
就像是<i>塞尔达</i>大师。
[laughs]
[笑]
Thanks.
Yes. <i>Zelda</i> worked.
谢谢。
是的。<i>塞尔达</i>这个礼物送对了。
One down.
一个搞定了。
Lindsay, for you,
林赛，给你，
I have an assortment
of very angsty teenage music
我准备了一系列
非常忧郁的青少年音乐
for your listening pleasure.
供你欣赏。
[laughs]
[Leigh] Thank you?
[笑]
[Leigh] 谢谢？
No, thank you.
不，谢谢您。
Nice to meet you,
John Zorin,
很高兴认识您，
约翰·卓宁，
Mom’s friend from church.
我妈妈在教堂的朋友。
Where are you going?
I have homework.
你要去哪？
我有作业要做。
[sighs heavily]
[Jeffrey] It’s okay.
[重重叹气]
[Jeffrey] 没关系。
[laughs]
Maybe next time.
[笑]
也许下次吧。
Okay?
[Leigh groans]
好吗？
[Leigh 发出不满的哼声]
All right? Don’t worry.
[sighs]
好吧？别担心。
[叹气]
I, uh, also happened
to have gotten you something,
我，呃，正好
也给你带了点东西，
Miss Leigh.
Oh.
Leigh小姐。
哦。
[Leigh]
This is all so sweet.
[chuckles]
[Leigh]
这一切真是太贴心了。
[轻笑]
I’m sorry about Lindsay.
我为林赛的事感到抱歉。
I-I thought this might be
hard for her.
我-我本来就觉得
这对她来说会很难接受。
[Jeffrey]
Yeah. No, and, look,
I understand that.
[杰弗里]
是的。不，而且，你看，
这个我能理解。
[Dee]
This one has to go on top.
[迪伊]
这个必须放在最上面。
[Jeffrey]
Yeah, the top, top part.
[杰弗里]
对，最顶上那部分。
And this one
has to go...
而这个
必须放到...
[Jeffrey] But wait,
where’s the light...
[杰弗里] 但是等等，
灯在哪里...
[Dee]
Wait, you got to connect.
[迪伊]
等等，你得先连接好。
[Jeffrey]
Oh, the click.
[chuckles]
[杰弗里]
哦，咔哒一声。
[轻笑]
I love the click.
我喜欢这个咔哒声。
And this one
has to go on that.
[Leigh] Dee?
而这一块
必须装在那个上面。
[Leigh] 迪伊？
Yeah.
嗯。
It’s 11:00.
Past 11:00.
已经11点了。
过了11点了。
Oh, come on,
let us finish this. Please?
哦，拜托，
让我们完成这个吧。求你了？
Please?
She’s, like, the best builder.
求你了？
她可是，最棒的搭建者。
We’re like 20 pieces away
from the end.
我们大概就差20块
就完成了。
[Dee]
Yeah, please, Mom.
[迪伊]
是啊，拜托了，妈妈。
So close.
Another time, okay?
就差一点了。
下次吧，好吗？
[Jeffrey]
Okay.
[杰弗里]
好吧。
I had the best time
with you.
我玩得非常开心
和你一起。
Okay?
Yeah.
好吗？
嗯。
[grunts]
[咕哝声]
[Jeffrey]
<i>Can I see you again?</i>
[杰弗里]
<i>我能再见到你吗？</i>
I’d like that.
我很乐意。
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- 是吗？
- 是啊。
So, if it’s late,
I’ll just come and, like,
tap on your window?
所以，如果时间晚了，
我就过来，然后，
敲你的窗户？
Oh.
[snickers]
哦。
[窃笑]
I don’t know if I’m a...
我不确定我是不是那种...
"tap on the window"
kind of girl, John.
“敲窗户”
类型的女孩，约翰。
No?
不是？
All right, how about I just
knock on the front door?
好吧，那我直接
敲前门怎么样？
Okay.
好的。
[piano playing
"I’ll be Home"]
[钢琴演奏
《我会回家》]
[Pastor Ron]
<i>♪ I’ll be home ♪</i>
[罗恩牧师]
<i>♪ 我会回家 ♪</i>
<i>♪ I’ll be home ♪</i>
<i>♪ When your nights
are troubled ♪</i>
<i>♪ 当你的夜晚
充满困扰 ♪</i>
<i>♪ And you’re all alone ♪</i>
<i>♪ 当你孤身一人 ♪</i>
[choir] <i>♪ Ooh ♪
♪ When you’re feeling down ♪</i>
[合唱团] <i>♪ 呜 ♪
♪ 当你情绪低落 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Ooh ♪
♪ You need some sympathy ♪</i>
<i>♪ 呜 ♪</i>
♪ 你需要些许慰藉 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Ooh ♪</i>
<i>♪ 呜 ♪</i>
<i>♪ There’s no one else around ♪</i>
<i>♪ 身边空无一人 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Ooh ♪
♪ To keep you company ♪</i>
<i>♪ 呜 ♪</i>
♪ 陪伴在你身旁 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Ooh ♪</i>
<i>♪ 呜 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Ah ♪
♪ Remember, baby ♪</i>
<i>♪ 啊 ♪</i>
♪ 记住，宝贝 ♪</i>
<i>♪ You can always ♪</i>
<i>♪ 你永远可以 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Count on me ♪
♪ Count on me ♪</i>
<i>♪ 依靠我 ♪</i>
♪ 依靠我 ♪</i>
<i>♪ I’ll be home ♪</i>
<i>♪ 我会在家 ♪</i>
<i>♪ I’ll be home
I’ll be home ♪</i>
<i>♪ 我会在家</i>
我会在家 ♪</i>
<i>♪ I’ll be home ♪</i>
<i>♪ 我会在家 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Wherever you may wander ♪</i>
<i>♪ 无论你漂泊何方 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Wherever you may roam ♪</i>
<i>♪ 无论你流浪何处 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Ooh ♪
♪ You come back ♪</i>
<i>♪ 哦 ♪</i>
♪ 当你归来 ♪</i>
<i>♪ I’ll be waiting here
for you ♪</i>
<i>♪ 我会在此等候</i>
着你 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Ooh ♪</i>
<i>♪ 哦 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Ah ♪
♪ I’ll be here ♪</i>
<i>♪ 啊 ♪</i>
♪ 我会在此 ♪</i>
<i>♪ To comfort you ♪</i>
<i>♪ 安慰你 ♪</i>
<i>♪ And see you through ♪
♪ And see you through ♪</i>
<i>♪ 陪你度过难关 ♪</i>
♪ 我会陪你度过 ♪</i>
<i>♪ I’ll be home
I’ll be home ♪</i>
<i>♪ 我将归家
我将归家 ♪</i>
[Leigh] Goodbye, Halloween.
<i>♪ I’ll be home ♪</i>
[莉] 再见，万圣节。
<i>♪ 我将归家 ♪</i>
<i>Turkey time.</i>
<i>火鸡时间到了。</i>
[song fades]
[歌曲淡出]
[Leigh]
<i>Don’t hit the light.</i>
[Otis] <i>I won’t.</i>
[莉]
<i>别关灯。</i>
[奥蒂斯] <i>我不会的。</i>
Yeah, maybe next year
we should get
an inflatable Otis.
是啊，也许明年
我们应该弄个
充气奥蒂斯。
[Otis mutters]
[clicks tongue]
[奥蒂斯咕哝着]
[咂舌]
Hey. I-I’m not
stepping in this time.
嘿。我-我这次
不会插手了。
Okay? You got to do it.
You got to do it.
好吗？你得自己来。
你得自己来。
You got to punch the bully
in the nose, you know?
你得对着霸凌者的鼻子
对着他鼻子来一拳，懂吗？
[keyboard clicking]
[knocking on door]
[键盘敲击声]
[敲门声]
- My man, Otis.
- Yeah.
- 我的老兄，奥蒂斯。
- 嗯。
Yeah. I need to tell you
something, Mitch.
是啊。米奇，我得告诉你
一件事。
- Whoa, okay.
- Yeah.
- 哇，好吧。
- 对。
I mean-- okay. What?
我是说——好吧。什么事？
Um...
[breathing heavily]
呃...
[沉重呼吸声]
What?
什么？
Uh...
嗯...
[Otis stammering]
[Jeffrey] Please say it.
[奥蒂斯结结巴巴]
[杰弗瑞] 快说吧。
<i>No, I’m sorry.
Um, I’m just...
What, what?</i>
<i>不，抱歉。
呃，我只是...
什么，什么？</i>
<i>Uh, I was, I was, um...</i>
Say it.
<i>呃，我，我是，嗯...</i>
说吧。
<i>Otis, come on. I...</i>
<i>奥蒂斯，快点。我...</i>
[Jeffrey] Just say it.
[杰弗里] 直接说出来。
<i>I wanted to tell you I-I...
What?</i>
<i>我想告诉你我-我...</i>
什么？</i>
<i>I sweeped up the stockroom
like you said.</i>
<i>我打扫了储藏室
按你说的。</i>
<i>Okay, is that it?
Yeah.</i>
<i>好，就这事？
是的。</i>
No. No.
不。不是。
[Jeffrey]
<i>My mom used to tell me
be careful what you touch.</i>
[杰弗里]
<i>我妈妈过去常告诉我
要小心你触碰的东西。</i>
<i>She said that moving one grain
of sand changes everything</i>
<i>她说移动一粒
沙子就能改变</i>
<i>in the whole universe.</i>
<i>整个宇宙中的一切。</i>
<i>I think people call it
the butterfly effect.</i>
<i>我想人们称之为
蝴蝶效应。</i>
<i>That just one butterfly
flapping its wings can</i>
<i>就是一只蝴蝶
扇动翅膀就能</i>
<i>make a hurricane
on the other side of the world.</i>
<i>引发一场飓风
在世界另一端。</i>
<i>And before we know it, we’re
banging into each other’s paths</i>
<i>而我们还未察觉时，就
闯入了彼此的人生轨迹</i>
<i>and changing what happens.</i>
<i>并改变了既定的走向。</i>
[Leigh]
Are you sure you want bangs?
[莉]
你确定要剪刘海吗？
Sure.
当然。
It’s a big change.
这可是个大改变。
Thing is about bangs,
关于刘海的问题是，
there’s only about
one in a thousand people
大概只有
千分之一的人
that actually look good
with bangs,
真正适合
留刘海，
but good news is I think that
you might be one of them.
不过好消息是，我觉得
你可能是其中之一。
[laughs softly]
[轻声笑]
Oh, God.
哦，天哪。
[Jeffrey]
<i>No one notices the butterfly
flapping its wings</i>
[杰弗里]
<i>无人留意那只蝴蝶
<i>直到蝴蝶扇动翅膀</i>
<i>until everyone
feels the storm.</i>
<i>直到所有人</i>
<i>都感受到风暴来临。</i>
<i>I knew a storm was coming.</i>
<i>我早知道风暴将至。</i>
<i>I knew if I stayed
in one place too long,</i>
<i>我知道如果我</i>
<i>在同一个地方停留太久，</i>
<i>eventually someone
would recognize me.</i>
<i>迟早会有人</i>
<i>认出我。</i>
<i>I knew I had to leave.</i>
<i>我知道我必须离开。</i>
<i>I just didn’t want
to go alone.</i>
<i>我只是不想</i>
<i>独自一人离开。</i>
[Jeffrey chuckles]
<i>You think you could
ever just move somewhere else?</i>
[杰弗里轻笑]
<i>你觉得你能</i>
<i>就这么搬到别处去吗？</i>
Like a beach or something?
Start over in a new place?
比如海边之类的？
在一个新地方重新开始？
I don’t know, John.
我不知道，约翰。
I-I need to come back here,
you know?
我-我得回到这里来，
你明白吗？
We could take the girls.
我们可以带上女儿们。
Just pack up and go.
收拾行李就走。
Mm. That’s...
嗯。那...
No, I can’t do that.
不，我做不到。
I can’t do that.
我做不到。
My life is here,
John.
我的生活在这里，
约翰。
["Don’t Speak" by No Doubt
playing over headphones]
["别说话" - No Doubt乐队
通过耳机播放]
[Mitch]
<i>♪ You’re letting go ♪</i>
[米奇]
<i>♪ 你正在放手 ♪</i>
<i>♪ And if it’s real ♪</i>
<i>♪ 如果这是真的 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Well, I don’t want to know ♪</i>
<i>♪ 嗯，我不想知道 ♪</i>
[Mitch grunting rhythmically]
[米奇有节奏地哼哼]
<i>♪ Don’t speak... ♪</i>
<i>♪ 别说话... ♪</i>
[water running]
[Mitch singing in distance]
[水流声]
[米奇在远处唱歌]
<i>♪ Stop explaining ♪</i>
[water stops]
<i>♪ 别再解释 ♪</i>
[水声停止]
<i>♪ Don’t tell me
’Cause it hurts ♪</i>
<i>♪ 别告诉我
因为那很伤人 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Don’t speak ♪</i>
<i>♪ 别说话 ♪</i>
<i>♪ I know what you’re... ♪</i>
[grunts]
<i>♪ 我知道你... ♪</i>
[闷哼声]
<i>♪ I don’t need your reasons ♪</i>
<i>♪ 我不需要你的理由 ♪</i>
[muffled]
<i>♪ Don’t tell me
’Cause it hurts ♪</i>
[闷响]
<i>♪ 别告诉我
因为那很伤人 ♪</i>
[song continues
over headphones]
[歌声继续
通过耳机]
<i>♪ Our memories ♪</i>
<i>♪ 我们的回忆 ♪</i>
<i>♪ They can be inviting ♪</i>
<i>♪ 它们可能诱人 ♪</i>
<i>♪ But some
Erotically enticing ♪</i>
<i>♪ 但有些
情色撩人 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Writing ♪</i>
<i>♪ 书写 ♪</i>
<i>♪ As we die ♪</i>
<i>♪ 当我们逝去 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Both you and I... ♪</i>
<i>♪ 你和我都... ♪</i>
[singing fades]
[歌声渐弱]
<i>♪ Stop explaining ♪</i>
<i>♪ 别再解释 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Don’t tell me
’Cause it hurts ♪</i>
<i>♪ 别告诉我
因为那很伤人 ♪</i>
<i>♪ No, no, no, no, no ♪</i>
<i>♪ 不，不，不，不，不 ♪</i>
[gasps] What the fuck?
[倒吸一口气] 搞什么鬼？
[yells]
[大喊]
What? Oh, my God!
什么？哦，我的天！
[Jeffrey yelling]
Oh, my God!
[杰弗瑞大喊]
哦，我的天！
[Jeffrey continues yelling]
[杰弗瑞持续大喊]
[door opens]
[alarm wailing]
[门开了]
[警报鸣响]
[grunting]
[咕哝声]
[panting]
[喘息声]
[alarm continues wailing]
[警报持续鸣响]
[grunting]
[咕哝声]
[clattering]
[grunts]
[哐当声]
[咕哝声]
[alarm continues wailing]
[警报持续鸣响]
[sirens wailing outside]
[外面警笛声鸣响]
[siren whoops]
[警笛鸣叫声]
[sirens wailing]
[警笛声鸣响]
[alarm continues wailing]
[警报持续鸣响]
[Mitch over headphones]
<i>Oh, my God,
there’s a lot of you.</i>
[耳机中米奇的声音]
<i>我的天啊，</i>
<i>你们来了这么多人。</i>
<i>He’s-he’s big. He’s naked!</i>
<i>他...他体型很大。他光着身子！</i>
<i>He came at me.</i>
<i>他刚才袭击我。</i>
[officer]
<i>Sir, is he still here?</i>
[警官]
<i>先生，他还在这里吗？</i>
[Mitch]
<i>I don’t know.</i>
[米奇]
<i>我不知道。</i>
<i>I heard the-the outer...
the alarm door went off.</i>
<i>我听到那个...外层的...</i>
<i>警报门响了。</i>
[officer]
<i>So he may have gone outside?</i>
[警官]
<i>所以他可能已经出去了？</i>
[Mitch] <i>Uh, yes.</i>
[officer]
Charlotte Police!
[米奇] <i>呃，是的。</i>
[警官]
夏洛特警察！
[officer 2] Charlotte Police!
[officer]
Charlotte Police!
[警官2] 夏洛特警察！
[警官]
夏洛特警察！
Police department!
警察局！
[indistinct shouting]
Police department!
[模糊的喊叫声]
警察局！
Police department!
[siren whooping]
[警笛鸣响]
[officer]
<i>The alarm was going off.</i>
[警员]
<i>警报器当时在响。</i>
<i>When we came back here,
the door was ajar,</i>
<i>当我们回到这里时，
门是虚掩着的，</i>
<i>so we really believe
he went out this way.</i>
<i>所以我们真的认为
他是从这条路出去的。</i>
[Mitch] <i>We could watch
the whole thing, Officer,</i>
[米奇] <i>我们可以查看
整个过程的，警官，</i>
<i>’cause I know how to... press
"play" on this thing, so...</i>
<i>因为我知道怎么...按
这个玩意儿的"播放"键，所以...</i>
[Scheimreif] <i>Mitch? Yeah?</i>
[沙伊姆赖夫] <i>米奇？什么事？</i>
<i>The good news is
you have surveillance cameras</i>
<i>好消息是
你的店里装满了</i>
<i>all over the store.</i>
[Mitch] <i>Yes. Yes.</i>
<i>监控摄像头。</i>
[Mitch] <i>是的是的。</i>
[Scheimreif]
<i>Bad news...</i>
<i>坏消息是...</i>
<i>is none of them
were recording.</i>
<i>它们全都</i>
没有在录像。</i>
You need
to fix that.
你得</i>
解决这个问题。</i>
Now, besides
the naked guy,
have you noticed
那么，除了</i>
那个裸体男人，</i>
你有没有注意到</i>
anything strange
happening around here?
有什么奇怪的事情</i>
在这里发生？</i>
Uh, uh...
呃，呃...</i>
Uh, well, we’re-we’re missing
a lot of gaming inventory.
呃，那个，我们-我们丢失了</i>
大量的游戏库存。</i>
[mutters softly]
[低声咕哝]
What’s a lot?
大量是多少？</i>
A substantial amount.
相当可观的数量。</i>
[Scheimreif] <i>You’re gonna
have to get some real security
in here, Mitch.</i>
[Scheimreif] <i>你得</i>
弄点真正的安保措施</i>
你得找些真正的保安来，米奇。
[reporter]
<i>Workers at this Toys "R" Us</i>
[记者]
这家玩具反斗城的员工们
<i>are prepping
for the holiday rush,</i>
正在为假日购物潮
做准备，
<i>but store manager
Mitch Haggin says</i>
但店长
米奇·哈金表示
<i>he did not expect to see
what he saw this morning:</i>
他没想到今天早上
会看到这样的景象：
<i>a strong, very tall, naked man.</i>
一个强壮、非常高大的裸体男子。
[Mitch over TV]
<i>Uh, a-a naked guy ran at me.</i>
[米奇在电视上]
呃，一个裸男朝我冲过来。
<i>I think he was gonna kill me,
and I ran away,</i>
我觉得他是想杀了我，
然后我就跑开了，
<i>locked myself in my office.</i>
把自己锁在了办公室里。
[reporter]
<i>When I asked if the naked man</i>
[记者]
当我问及裸男是否会
<i>would scare off
holiday shoppers,</i>
吓跑
假日购物者时，
<i>Mr. Haggin said he was hiring
round-the-clock security.</i>
哈金先生表示他正在聘请
<i>哈金先生表示他已雇佣了全天候保安。</i>
<i>We have a really good security
system here now, for sure.</i>
<i>我们现在这里有一套非常完善的安保</i>
系统，这是肯定的。</i>
<i>Families can feel safe.</i>
<i>家庭可以感到安全。</i>
<i>This is a safe place
to come for Christmas.</i>
<i>这是一个安全的</i>
圣诞节购物场所。</i>
[Leigh]
I think it looks great.
[TV clicks off]
[莉]</i>
我觉得看起来很棒。
[电视咔哒一声关闭]</i>
Hi.
你好。
We’re almost
ready to go.
我们差不多</i>
准备好了。</i>
[Pastor Ron]
<i>Lord, we want to thank you</i>
[罗恩牧师]</i>
<i>主啊，我们感谢您</i>
for this wonderful food,
赐予这美好的食物，</i>
and we want to thank you
for the gift of family. Amen.
我们也感谢您</i>
赐予我们家庭的恩赐。阿门。</i>
[all]
Amen.
[众人]</i>
阿门。
Happy Thanksgiving.
感恩节快乐。
[happy chatter]
[愉快的交谈声]
[Eileen]
So, Leigh.
Yes?
[艾琳]
那么，莉。
怎么了？
Why don’t you tell us all
that story about the naked man.
你何不跟我们大家讲讲
那个裸体男人的故事。
[chuckles]
Oh, it-it’s nothing, y’all.
[轻笑]
哦，没——没什么，大家。
It... it was cold outside,
外面...外面很冷，
and a homeless man
needed to take a shower.
一个无家可归的人
需要洗个澡。
Yeah, but what if
he’s also a killer?
是啊，但如果
他也是个杀手呢？
He’s...
Stop being overdramatic.
他...
别这么小题大做。
He’s not a killer.
他不是杀手。
[chuckles]
Your mom’s totally right.
[轻笑]
你妈说得完全正确。
He’s definitely not
a killer.
他绝对不是
杀手。
You don’t know that,
John.
你又不确定，
约翰。
Well, if he was a killer,
he’d have killed him, right?
嗯，如果他是杀手，
他早就杀了他了，对吧？
Uh, the paper said today
that there was $10,000
in video games stolen.
呃，报纸上说今天
有价值一万美金
的游戏光盘被盗。
Mm.
嗯。
[Randy] I don’t know
if that’s a coincidence or not.
[兰迪] 我不知道
这是不是巧合。
[Eileen]
That is a lot of money.
[艾琳]
那可是一大笔钱。
[Lindsay]
Well, I don’t know, Mom.
[林赛]
嗯，我不知道，妈。
Maybe you should quit.
也许你应该辞职。
You have
a master’s degree,
你拥有
硕士学位，
and I don’t think
it’s worth the risk.
而且我认为
这不值得去冒险。
It seems scary
over there.
那边的情况
似乎很吓人。
I mean, that’s not
the worst idea,
I guess.
我的意思是，
这主意不算最糟，
我想。
I like my job.
[Randy] Wait. Hold up.
我喜欢我的工作。
[兰迪] 等等，等一下。
Earlier, you just made it seem
like it wasn’t dangerous.
刚才你还说得
好像没什么危险似的。
So, if it’s not dangerous,
then-then why does
she have to quit so suddenly?
既然没有危险，
那为什么
她要突然辞职呢？
[Pastor Ron] Yeah.
I don’t know.
I’m sorry.
[罗恩牧师] 是啊。
我不知道。
抱歉。
Uh, did I, did I say
she had to quit?
呃，我说过
她必须辞职吗？
I don’t think I did, actually.
实际上，我觉得我没说过。
I think I was just agreeing
with Lindsay down here.
我想我只是在附和
下面的林赛。
I was just saying here
that Lindsay
我刚才在这里只是说
林赛
actually has
a great idea.
实际上
有个好主意。
If she wants to quit,
如果她想辞职，
then she would
have more time
with her girls.
那么她就能
有更多时间
陪她的女儿们。
Yeah.
[Pastor Ron]
Now, everybody,
是的。
[罗恩牧师]
好了，各位，
let’s not get too serious,
because, uh...
我们别太严肃了，
因为，呃...
[laughing] I just think
it’s kind of funny.
[笑着] 我只是觉得
这有点好笑。
I imagine the guy,
he’s just going to work,
我想象那个家伙，
他正要去上班，
just a normal day,
and then he sees a naked guy
就和平常一样，
然后他看到一个裸男
running around
inside his toy store.
[laughter]
到处乱跑
在他玩具店里。
[笑声]
[Kami] Makes me want
to get a job there, actually.
[卡米] 这反倒让我想
去那儿找份工作了。
[laughter]
[笑声]
Oh, Kami, bless you.
哦，卡米，愿主保佑你。
Yeah, I just think
it’s really funny,
that’s all.
是啊，我只是觉得
这真的很好笑，
仅此而已。
I don’t think
it’s funny, Ron.
我不觉得
这好笑，罗恩。
I-I think it’s sad.
我——我觉得这很可悲。
I mean,
someone’s so desperate
我的意思是，
有人绝望到
they had to bathe
in a toy store sink,
不得不在
玩具店的水槽里洗澡，
while we eat
and laugh about it?
我们却在吃饭
还拿这个开玩笑？
I mean, maybe we aren’t
Good Samaritans.
我是说，或许我们算不上
什么乐善好施的人
[Eileen]
Mm.
[艾琳]
嗯
[Lindsay] Maybe you aren’t
making the best decisions.
[林赛] 也许你做的
并不是最佳选择
Excuse me, ma’am?
请问您说什么？
Choosing to work there
while Dee and I
are home alone,
选择在那里工作
而我和迪
只能待在家里
waiting for someone
to pick us up
to take us places?
等着有人
来接我们
带我们出门？
Like, we...
Whoa, whoa.
比如说我们...
喂，喂
If we’re being honest,
you’re old enough
to drive yourself.
老实说
你这个年纪
早该自己开车了
[Lindsay]
I don’t have a license.
[林赛]
我没有驾照。
I told you
I would teach you.
Okay?
我告诉过你
我会教你的。
好吗？
[Lindsay] I can’t even
sit in the car with you.
[林赛] 我甚至不能
和你一起坐在车里。
And now that Dad’s not here,
you bring around this weirdo,
既然爸爸不在这里了，
你就带这个怪人回来，
and we’re supposed
to just accept it?
而我们
就该接受吗？
I-I hope the sex
is worth it.
我-我希望那档子事
值得你这么做。
[gasps]
[Pastor Ron]
Hey, hey, hey.
[倒吸一口气]
[罗恩牧师]
嘿，嘿，嘿。
[Leigh]
Lin...
[莉]
林...
[Leigh clears throat
softly]
[莉清了清嗓子
轻声]
Sorry.
抱歉。
[chair scrapes on floor]
[椅子在地板上刮擦]
[Kami whispers]
Our church.
[Pastor Ron] Yeah.
[卡米低语]
我们的教堂。
[罗恩牧师] 是的。
[quiet chatter]
[低声交谈]
[phone ringing]
[电话铃声]
[Pastor Ron]
Wow.
[罗恩牧师]
哇哦。
[phone continues ringing]
[电话继续响铃]
Hello?
[Jeffrey over phone] <i>Uh, hi.</i>
喂？
[杰弗里，电话中] <i>呃，你好。</i>
[whispering]
Um, this is Cousin Oliver.
[耳语声]
嗯，我是奥利弗表弟。
I was just calling
for Steve.
我打电话来
是想找史蒂夫。
<i>It’s 7:00 in the morning.</i>
<i>现在才早上7点。</i>
[Jeffrey]
Uh, it’s also December 1st,
[杰弗里]
呃，今天也是12月1号，
and we had a conversation
a few months back
我们几个月前谈过，
几个月前
that I should call back
on December 1st.
我该在
12月1日回电。
<i>Yeah, you just call back.
He’s sleeping.</i>
<i>对，你直接回电。
他在睡觉。</i>
Okay, well, can you
just wake him up for me?
好吧，那你能不能
帮我叫醒他？
Um, just tell him
it’s Cousin Oliver.
嗯，就跟他说
是奥利弗表弟。
All right?
It’s urgent.
行吗？
有急事。
Baby.
Mm. Mm.
亲爱的。
嗯。嗯。
It’s your cousin.
It’s Cousin Oliver.
是你表弟。
是奥利弗表弟。
[groans] Tell him I’m asleep.
[呻吟] 告诉他我睡着了。
[muttering]
Motherfucker. Goddamn.
[咕哝]
混蛋。真该死。
He says...
We can do it Sunday.
他说...
我们可以周日再办。
...he’s asleep and that
...他睡着了，然后
<i>you should come
see him next Sunday.</i>
<i>你应该
下周日来看他。</i>
Next Sunday.
Okay, great. Is he
still in Fayetteville?
下周日。
好的，太好了。他
还在费耶特维尔吗？
<i>No. No.
It’s the Twin Pines Motel.</i>
<i>不。不在。
是双松汽车旅馆。</i>
Twin Pines. Okay.
双松。好的。
<i>Room 204.</i>
<i>204房间。</i>
204. I got it.
[Steve] <i>And don’t be</i>
204。我记下了。
[史蒂夫] <i>还有，别他妈
a fucking dumbass
and take the bus.
像个傻逼一样
去坐公交车。</i>
He says don’t be a fucking
dumbass and take the bus.
他说别他妈
像个傻逼一样去坐公交车。
<i>He wants to know
if you got a car.</i>
<i>他想知道
你是否有车。</i>
[Jeffrey] Yep. Tell the sarge,
uh, I’ll take care of that
[杰弗里] 有。告诉中士，
呃，我会处理好的
and I’ll see him on Sunday
as scheduled.
我会在周日
如期去见他的。
[phone beeps]
[电话哔哔声]
[dishes clatter]
[盘子碰撞声]
H-Hi. Morning.
早...早上好。
You didn’t tell me
you had to take a trip.
你没告诉我
你要出门一趟。
You weren’t supposed
to hear that.
你本来不该
听到的。
[laughs]
Okay.
[笑]
好吧。
Look, it’s not a big deal.
听着，没什么大不了的。
I just have to go
and just check in.
我只是需要去
报个到。
That’s all.
Okay.
就这样。
好的。
Mwah.
啵。
Morning, Lindsay.
早上好，林赛。
Good morning, Leigh.
Good morning, Dee.
早上好，莉。
早上好，迪。
Everybody want to say
"good morning"?
大家都想说
"早上好"吗？
[Dee] Morning, John.
[Jeffrey chuckles]
[迪] 早上好，约翰。
[杰弗瑞轻笑]
All right, who wants
to apologize first, hmm?
好了，谁想
先道歉，嗯？
No? You?
没有吗？你呢？
Come on, guys.
[stammers]
拜托，各位。
[结结巴巴]
Nobody has anything
to say to each other?
难道没人
想对彼此说点什么吗？
Look, families fight.
听着，家人之间难免吵架。
That’s fine,
but they also make up.
这没什么，
但他们也会和好。
Come on.
来吧。
I’m sorry for the way
I’ve been acting, Lindsay.
林赛，我为
我最近的表现道歉。
[knocks on counter]
Great work.
[敲了敲柜台]
说得好。
I shouldn’t have said
the thing about sex
in front of Dee.
我不该
关于性爱的那件事
当着迪的面说出来
Mm. Yeah.
嗯。是啊。
And...
还有...
And? You got it.
还有？你说对了。
And I need a ride
to Doug’s.
我需要搭个车
去道格家
Nope. That wasn’t...
不行。那不是...
You aren’t getting
a ride anywhere.
你哪儿都
别想搭车
Do you have any idea
how much you embarrassed me
last night?
你知不知道
你昨晚让我
有多难堪？
I embarrassed you?
我让你难堪？
John, will you drive me?
约翰，你能开车送我吗？
You do not get to abuse him
and then ask him for favors.
你不能欺负了他
又找他帮忙
[Jeffrey] It’s okay.
I-I don’t mind driving her.
[杰弗里] 没关系
我-我不介意送她
No, stay out of this, John.
See, he doesn’t mind.
不，约翰你别插手
看吧，他并不介意。
If she wants to go somewhere,
she can learn to drive.
如果她想去什么地方，
她可以学着自己开车。
I’m not driving in that car
with that stick shift
with you ever.
我才不要开那辆车
用那个手动挡
永远都不要和你一起开。
Well, then I guess
you’ll never go anywhere again!
嗯，那我猜
你以后哪儿也去不了了！
[Jeffrey]
Okay, time-out. Time-out.
Ever!
[杰弗里]
好了，暂停。暂停一下。
永远都不要！
I’m sorry, can I ask my mom
to drive me places
不好意思，我能让我妈妈
开车送我去别的地方吗
’cause she’s my mother?
[Jeffrey] Okay, stop.
因为她是我妈妈？
[杰弗里] 好了，别说了。
I have an idea, okay?
我有个主意，好吗？
I have an idea. Hear me out.
It’s a great idea.
我有个主意。听我说完。
这是个很棒的主意。
We need a beater.
我们需要一辆破车。
What even is a beater,
John?
破车到底是什么东西，
约翰？
["Little Drummer Boy"
by Jim Nabors playing]
《小小鼓手》
吉姆·内伯斯演唱]
<i>♪ Come, they told me ♪</i>
<i>♪ 来吧，他们告诉我 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Pa, rum, pum, pum, pum... ♪</i>
[Jeffrey speaks indistinctly]
<i>♪ 啪，隆，砰，砰，砰... ♪</i>
[杰弗里含糊不清地说着]
[salesman] That’s a nice ride
right there, huh?
[销售员] 这辆车真不错
对吧？
Classic 1999
with very low mileage.
经典的1999年款
里程数非常低。
[Jeffrey] Yeah?
[salesman]
Great color, too.
[杰弗里] 是吗？
[销售员]
颜色也很棒。
Awesome family car.
很棒的家庭用车。
[Jeffrey]
It’s automatic.
[杰弗里]
是自动挡的。
[salesman]
It is automatic.
Great price.
[销售员]
是自动挡。
价格很划算。
You guys
want to try it out?
Yeah.
你们
想试试看吗？
好啊。
Got the keys right here.
Look at that.
钥匙就在这儿。
看看这个。
[sighs]
It’s nice seats, right?
[叹气]
座椅很不错吧？
You know, modern cars
just don’t have the same feel.
你知道，现代汽车
就是没有同样的感觉。
This is kind of like
the golden era.
这有点像
黄金时代。
The ’90s. [sighs]
九十年代。[叹气]
You know, just... [stammers]
They don’t make modern cars
like this anymore, you know?
你知道，就是…[结巴]
他们不再生产这样的
现代汽车了，你知道吗？
Yeah.
These-these are like sofas.
是啊。
这些——这些就像沙发一样。
You guys buckled up?
[Leigh] Yeah, yeah.
你们系好安全带了吗？
[Leigh] 好了，好了。
Any cops around here ever?
Oh, no, no.
这附近有过警察吗？
哦，没有，没有。
Nobody’s gonna stop you here.
这儿没人会拦你的。
Just gonna push it
just a little bit.
只是想稍微
提点速。
[engine revving]
[tires squealing]
[引擎轰鸣]
[轮胎尖啸]
[salesman chuckles]
Okay.
[销售员轻笑]
好的。
Okay.
[girls laugh]
好的。
[女孩们大笑]
[chuckles]
Oh, oh, oh, oh.
[轻笑]
哦，哦，哦，哦。
It’s got some horsepower.
Okay.
这车马力不小。
好的。
All right, all right.
好了，好了。
Got a nice V-6...
[engine revving]
配备不错的V6发动机...
[引擎轰鸣]
Okay. Okay.
[yells nervously]
好的。好的。
[紧张地大喊]
[tires squealing]
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
[轮胎尖啸]
嘿，嘿，嘿，嘿！
Hey, sir! Sir!
嘿，先生！先生！
Watch out!
Here we go.
小心！
开始了。
Oh. Oh! Oh!
[tires squealing]
哦。哦！哦！
[轮胎尖啸]
[girls scream]
[scream] Fuck!
[女孩们尖叫]
[尖叫] 操！
[girls laughing]
Fuck! Slow down!
Slow down!
[女孩们大笑]
操！慢点！
慢点！
Slow down!
Slow down! It’s a used car!
慢点！
慢点！这是辆二手车！
Slow down! [scream]
慢点！[尖叫]
Slow down! Slow down!
慢点！慢点！
[tires screeching]
<i>♪ I played my best for him ♪</i>
[轮胎刺耳声]
<i>♪ 我为他献上最好的演奏 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Pa, rum, pum, pum, pum... ♪</i>
<i>♪ 啪，隆隆，砰，砰，砰... ♪</i>
[yelping]
[惊叫声]
[Jeffrey and girls laughing]
[杰弗里和女孩们大笑]
You guys okay?
你们没事吧？
Motherfucker!
Yeah?
妈的！
嗯？
All right, good.
[laughing]
行，好的。
[笑]
What’s wrong with you, man?
你怎么回事啊，老兄？
[laughs] Calm down.
No, no, get out.
[笑] 冷静点。
不，不，下车。
Calm down. No, no, no.
Get out. Get out!
冷静。不，不，不。
下车。快下车！
I’m driving us back.
Lindsay, Lindsay. Stop.
我来开车载大家回去。
林赛，林赛。停下。
Calm down.
Lindsay, get up here.
You drive. You in the back.
冷静下来。
林赛，到前面来。
你开车。你到后座去。
No, maybe
she shouldn’t drive,
John.
不，也许
不该让她开车，
约翰。
No. No, she’s a kid!
She can’t drive!
不行。不行，她还是个孩子！
她不能开车！
It’s busy here. It’s busy.
No, she can drive.
Listen.
这里车很多。太繁忙了。
不，她能开。
听着。
No, give me the keys
- right now.
- No, no.
不，把钥匙给我
- 马上。
- 不，不行。
Stop, stop.
Calm down, okay?
停下，快停下。
冷静点，好吗？
How do you teach a kid to swim?
You throw them in the water.
你怎么教小孩游泳？
直接把他们扔进水里。
Right?
If you want her to drive,
对吧？
如果你想让她开车，
we got to let her drive.
[Dee] Oh, yeah.
Go, Lindsay.
就得让她开。
[迪伊] 哦，没错。
上吧，林赛。
[salesman]
Does she even have a license?
[销售员]
她真的有驾照吗？
[Jeffrey]
She has her permit.
[Leigh] No.
[杰弗里]
她有学习驾照。
[莉] 不行。
[salesman] No, you cannot
test-drive with a permit.
[销售员] 不，你不能
凭学习驾照不能试驾。
Look, listen,
I’m gonna purchase this car
听着，
只要这位小姐认可
if the young lady approves,
and I’m gonna pay cash.
我就要买这辆车，
而且我会付现金。
How’s that sound to you?
你觉得怎么样？
I’ll let you hold it.
我会让你拿着钱。
Come on.
来吧。
Yes.
好的。
Get up here.
You’re driving.
到前面来。
你来开车。
All right.
好的。
好了。
Seat belts. Safety first.
系好安全带，安全第一。
All right, this is not
a manual transmission.
好了，这不是
手动挡汽车。
This is an automatic,
so it’s so much easier.
这是自动挡，
所以简单多了。
You can just forget about
your left foot.
你完全可以不用管
你的左脚。
It’s all right foot.
只用右脚就行。
So put your right foot
on that brake right there,
所以把你的右脚
放在那个刹车踏板上，
the big pedal.
那个大的踏板。
Yep, push it all the way in.
All the way in. Real firm.
对，使劲踩到底。
踩到底。要踩实了。
Okay, now you’re gonna
take your right hand,
好，现在你用
你的右手，
you’re gonna pull that
towards you and down to "D."
把它朝你的方向
往下拉到"D"挡。
Perfect. Now let it go.
完美。现在松开手。
Back at two.
回到两点钟方向。
All right. We’re not
gonna worry about the gas.
好了。我们暂时
不用管油门。
You’re just gonna ease
your foot off the brake
你只需要慢慢
把脚从刹车踏板上抬起
and we’re just gonna
move forward, and that’s it.
然后我们就会
往前开，就这样。
All right? Take a big breath.
好吗？深呼吸。
You got this. [chuckles]
[Dee laughing]
你能行的。[轻笑]
[迪伊在笑]
[laughing]
You got it. Come on.
[笑]
你做到了。来吧。
You got it.
Go, go, go, go, go.
你做到了。
走，走，走，走，走。
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
That’s good.
对，对，对，对。
很好。
[Jeffrey] Nice.
[Leigh] Good one.
[杰弗里] 不错。
[利] 干得好。
All right, family.
好了，各位。
I always
love to take pictures
of my happy customers,
我总
喜欢给我的
开心顾客们拍照，
if you guys don’t mind.
如果你们不介意的话。
All right.
好的。
Big smile.
[camera clicks]
笑一笑。
[相机咔嚓声]
One more, one more.
[camera winding]
再来一张，再来一张。
[相机卷片声]
Now, let’s pretend your dad
almost crashed the car.
现在，假设你爸爸
差点把车撞了。
[Dee laughing]
[camera clicks]
[迪伊笑]
[相机咔嚓声]
All right.
[camera winding]
好了。
[相机卷片声]
[all chuckling]
Hey, great,
great stuff, guys.
[众人轻笑]
嘿，太棒了，
拍得真好，各位。
Thank you very much.
非常感谢。
You’re a better driver
than him.
[laughter]
你开车比他
强多了。
[笑声]
That’s true, actually.
I felt really, really safe
with you, so good job.
这倒是实话。
我觉得非常非常安全
和你在一起，所以干得好。
[growls playfully]
[ playful地低吼]
Oh, I’m glad.
哦，我很高兴。
Thank you, John.
Congrats, man.
谢谢你，约翰。
恭喜了，哥们。
Will you girls wait
in the car
while I talk to John
你们几个女孩能在
在车里
我和约翰说几句话
for just, like,
a minute? Here.
就
一分钟？给。
Okay.
好的。
[keys jingling]
[钥匙叮当声]
We got a beater.
[laughs]
我们买了辆破车。
[笑]
Yeah, we got a beater.
Yeah.
是啊，我们买了辆破车。
嗯。
[girls laugh]
[女孩们笑]
I have to say it.
我必须得说。
I did not like that driving.
Okay.
我不喜欢那样开车。
好吧。
I’m sorry. I know.
对不起，我知道。
I shouldn’t have done that.
我不该那样做。
Yeah.
是啊。
But Lindsay was a really,
really good first-time driver.
但林赛真的是个
非常棒的新手司机。
Wasn’t she?
She was great.
是吧？
她开得很棒。
Yeah.
She did so good.
是啊。
她表现得超好。
And-and-- I don’t know--
而且...那个...我说不好...
I think she’s starting
to like me.
我觉得她开始
喜欢上我了。
They both like you.
她们俩都喜欢你。
They really like you, okay?
她们真的喜欢你，好吗？
I like you.
我喜欢你。
Just... just need to slow it
down a little bit, okay?
只是...只是需要放慢
一点点节奏，好吗？
Okay.
好的。
And we don’t need
so many things, John.
我们不需要
那么多花样，约翰。
We just want you.
我们只要你这个人。
Just be you. Be normal.
做你自己就好。正常一点。
- I promise. The most normal.
- Okay.
- 我保证。会是最正常的。
- 好的。
You take your trip,
and when you come back,
你去你的旅行，
等你回来后，
we’ll have a-a few
normal nights, okay?
我们过几晚
平常日子，好吗？
No more stunt driving,
I promise.
不再飙车了，
我保证。
Okay.
好的。
[girls making
kissing noises]
[女孩们发出
亲吻声]
[chuckling]
[轻笑]
[Leigh]
Oh, gosh.
[莉]
哦，天哪。
[giggling,
making kissing noises]
[咯咯笑，
发出亲吻声]
I love John.
[Jeffrey]
Oh, my God.
我爱约翰。
[杰弗里]
哦，我的天。
The car. I love the car.
这辆车。我爱这辆车。
It’s the perfect car.
See you back at the house.
它是一辆完美的车。
回头家里见。
Okay.
好的。
[knocking]
[敲门声]
Hi.
你好。
Uh, Cousin Oliver.
[dog barks]
呃，奥利弗表弟。
[狗叫声]
Here for Steve.
Oh. Mm,
it’s a little early.
来找史蒂夫的。
哦。嗯，
有点早啊。
[chuckles]
[轻笑]
Hey, Steve?
[Steve] Yeah?
嘿，史蒂夫？
[史蒂夫] 怎么了？
Cousin Oliver’s
here.
奥利弗表弟
来了。
[dog barking]
[狗叫声]
Hello, dumb dog.
你好啊，笨狗。
Yeah, I knew you’d show up
at the crack of dawn
是啊，我就知道你会
天刚蒙蒙亮就出现
if I ain’t give you
a time.
如果我没给你
定个时间。
- Welcome home, Sarge.
- Man.
- 欢迎回家，中士。
- 老兄。
All right, you...
[grunting] Oh, man.
好吧，你...
[闷哼] 哦，天啊。
Yeah,
that is enough.
Yeah.
是啊，
够了。
嗯。
Damn, you look clean
for a motherfucker
that’s on the run.
该死，你看起来真干净
对于一个在逃的混蛋来说
真是干净。
I’m trying. I’m trying.
我在努力。我在努力。
Where you was
hiding out at, church?
你之前
是躲在教堂吗？
You know
I can’t tell you that.
你知道
我不能告诉你。
Seriously,
where you hiding out at?
说真的，
你到底躲在哪里？
No, I can’t tell you that.
You don’t want to know that.
不，我不能告诉你。
你不想知道那个。
You ain’t got no contact, right?
你没有联系任何人，对吧？
You ain’t
talking to nobody?
No, no.
你没有
没在跟任何人说话吗？
没有，没有。
Okay, ’cause you know
if you are,
I can’t help you.
好的，因为你知道
如果你有联系，
我就帮不了你了。
No, why would I do that?
没有，我怎么会那么做？
You good?
I’m good. I’m good.
你没事吧？
我没事。我没事。
Keep your eyes on me, then.
那就看着我。
Why you keep
darting them around?
你为什么一直
眼神躲闪？
I’m not darting them.
I’m looking right at you.
我没有躲闪。
我正看着你呢。
You sure
you’re all right?
Look.
你确定
你没事吗？
听着。
Okay.
好吧。
["Loyalty" by the
Tim Terry Experience playing]
[“忠诚” -
Tim Terry Experience 播放中]
[Steve] <i>We gonna
need to change that hair</i>
[史蒂夫] <i>我们得
得把头发弄一下</i>
<i>before we take the photo.</i>
<i>拍照前得先整理头发。</i>
<i>Uh, baby, what you think?
Wig? Dye?</i>
<i>呃，宝贝，你觉得呢？
假发？染发？</i>
For-for his hair.
是-是为了他的头发。
I think we do a wig.
我觉得用假发吧。
Yeah. Don’t worry, Jeff.
You’ll still be you.
嗯。别担心，杰夫。
你还是你。
But cuter.
Like Brad Pitt.
但会更可爱。
像布拉德·皮特那样。
Ugly-ass Brad Pitt.
丑毙了的布拉德·皮特。
[Steve]
Oh, my God.
[史蒂夫]
哦，天啊。
Baby, are you serious
about this?
宝贝，你是认真的吗
？
I’m-I’m...
[stammers]
我-我...
[结巴]
This is a panty dropper.
这简直让人把持不住。
Oh, my God.
Baby, come on.
哦，天啊。
宝贝，别这样。
Okay.
好的。
Oh. [groans]
哦。[呻吟]
You got to be
fucking kidding me, baby.
你肯定是在
跟我开玩笑吧，宝贝。
[Michelle]
Say hi, baby.
[米歇尔]
打个招呼，宝贝。
Wow.
哇哦。
Baby, th-that’s...
that’s a good one.
宝贝，这-这真是...
这个不错。
That’s good, right?
Yeah.
这很好，对吧？
是的。
This one feel good to you?
Mm-hmm.
这个你觉得舒服吗？
嗯哼。
Mm-hmm?
Feels like you could be
嗯哼？
感觉你可以
- this person for a while?
- Mm-hmm.
- 当这个人一段时间？
- 嗯哼。
- You ready?
- Mm-hmm.
- 准备好了吗？
- 嗯哼。
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Stop with the damn smiling.
等等，等等，等等，等等。
别他妈笑了。
Fuck you doing?
你搞什么鬼？
Just... normal face.
No, yeah, serious.
就…正常表情。
对，严肃点。
It’s like a...
it’s your passport, you know.
这就像是…
你的护照，你懂的。
You’re not allowed to smile.
不允许笑。
One, two, three.
一、二、三。
[camera beeps, clicks]
[相机发出哔声，咔嚓]
[whirring]
[嗡嗡声]
[Steve]
Read this shit. Study it.
[史蒂夫]
读读这玩意儿。好好研究。
All of it.
全部内容。
All right?
It’s gonna be the new you.
明白了吗？
这将是全新的你。
You’re Kenneth Owen Griffin.
你是肯尼斯·欧文·格里芬。
Born July 7, 1974,
from Lumberton, North Carolina.
出生于1974年7月7日，
来自北卡罗来纳州兰伯顿。
Now, I’m-a get
all your documents.
现在，我去拿
你所有的文件。
Don’t worry about shit.
别瞎操心。
Transfers, records--
I’ll have it all done, A to Z.
转账、记录——
我会全部搞定，从头到尾。
Okay. What-what are you
thinking, like 5K?
好吧。你...你觉着
大概要五千？
Oh, no, it’s gonna be
a lot more than that, man.
哦，不，这得要
多得多，老兄。
More than that?
How-how much more?
比那还多？
多...多少？
You think I don’t know
what you doing, huh?
你以为我不知道
你在干什么，嗯？
You probably got a girlfriend,
don’t you?
你八成有个女朋友，
对吧？
What? No.
什么？没有。
Yeah, you do.
不，你有的。
不，你肯定有。
Yeah, you not good
at this shit.
没错，你搞这破事
不太在行。
Good at what shit?
Being a criminal, nigga.
搞什么破事不在行？
当个罪犯啊，老兄。
Let me tell you something.
我跟你说啊。
Good criminals
are cold, calculating.
优秀的罪犯
都是冷酷且精于算计的。
You understand?
明白吗？
Now, you got
the calculation down,
现在，你
算计这方面是到位了，
but, man, you just... goofy.
但是，老兄，你就是……太滑稽了。
The price...
it’s gonna be 50K.
这个价钱……
要五万块。
All right?
行吗？
50? 50?
Yeah.
五万？五万？
对。
Hey, you a lot of risk, man.
Can you do it?
嘿，你这风险太大了，伙计。
你能搞定吗？
Okay. Yeah.
好吧。行。
How you gonna do it?
你打算怎么做？
I’ll get it.
我会搞到钱的。
我会搞到的。
Well, if you’re thinking about
using a gun, do me a favor.
不过，如果你在考虑
用枪的话，帮我个忙。
Stay the fuck off the TV.
别他妈的上电视。
Roofman, you understand
what I’m saying?
屋顶男，你明白
我的意思吗？
Don’t do anything stupid.
别做傻事。
[engine revving]
[引擎轰鸣]
[grunts]
[咕哝声]
[panting]
[喘息声]
Ow.
嗷。
[exhales]
Okay.
[呼气声]
好的。
Shit.
妈的。
What the...?
什么鬼...？
[panting]
[喘息声]
[crickets chirping]
[蟋蟀鸣叫]
Shit!
该死！
[shouts]
[喊叫声]
Shit!
该死！
Stupid idiot!
白痴！
[panting]
[喘息声]
[alarm blaring]
[警报大作]
[groans]
[呻吟声]
[alarm continues blaring]
[警报持续大作]
[door rattling]
[门嘎嘎作响]
[grunts]
[咕哝声]
[alarm ringing]
[警报鸣响]
[Mitch]
<i>90% of our annual sales happens
in the next two weeks.</i>
[米奇]
<i>我们90%的年销售额产生于
接下来的两周。</i>
<i>Think about that.</i>
<i>好好想想。</i>
<i>There’s gonna be
a lot of money coming in,</i>
<i>将会有
大笔资金涌入，</i>
<i>and we need to be ready
for it.</i>
<i>我们必须为此
做好准备。</i>
<i>Considering our recent setbacks,</i>
<i>考虑到我们最近的挫折，</i>
<i>I think we’re doing
pretty good.</i>
<i>我认为我们做得
相当不错。</i>
<i>You should be proud.
Come on.</i>
<i>你们应该感到自豪。
加油。</i>
Come on, guys.
Come on. Come on.
来吧，各位。
快点。快点。
But the ball game
starts now.
但真正的比赛
现在才开始。
[Mitch]
<i>We’re beefing up security
so the store is safe</i>
[米奇]
<i>我们正在加强安保
以确保商店安全</i>
<i>and families feel safe
in the store.</i>
<i>让每个家庭
在店里感到安心。</i>
Right on schedule.
完全准时。
<i>Because if our customers
have a good Christmas,</i>
<i>因为如果我们的顾客
能过个好圣诞节，</i>
then so do we.
我们也能。</i>
<i>You are so punctual, my friend.
I like it.</i>
<i>你真是守时啊，朋友。
我喜欢。</i>
<i>Your job is to sell toys.</i>
<i>你的工作是销售玩具。</i>
[Mitch]
<i>It’s gonna be a little bit
heavier this time around.</i>
[米奇]
<i>这次的份量
会稍微重一些。</i>
[straining]
<i>Yeah, getting a lot
of these lately.</i>
[用力]
<i>是啊，最近收到很多
最近这类东西可真不少。</i>
<i>It’s good for your arms,
muscles there.</i>
<i>这对你的手臂有好处，</i>
能练肌肉。</i>
[Mitch]
<i>We’re gonna open early</i>
[米奇]
<i>今年圣诞季我们将提早开门</i>
<i>and stay open late every day
this Christmas season,</i>
<i>并且每天都营业到很晚，</i>
</i>
<i>and that includes
Christmas Eve.</i>
<i>这其中也包括</i>
平安夜。</i>
I posted the new schedule.
我已经贴出了新的排班表。
Now, I know some of you
我知道你们当中有些人
are gonna have shifts
they don’t want,
不想要的班次，
but there’s no exceptions
or changes.
但没有任何例外
或变动。
You show up when your name
is on the schedule.
排班表上有你的名字，
你就得来上班。
<i>Now, let’s have
a happy Christmas.</i>
<i>现在，让我们共度</i>
一个快乐的圣诞节。</i>
<i>Let’s do this for the kids.</i>
<i>让我们为了孩子们加把劲。</i>
[clapping over headphones]
<i>Come on. Back to work.</i>
[耳机里传来鼓掌声]
<i>好了，回去工作吧。</i>
<i>♪ Oh, our Father is
The maker of Mary ♪</i>
<i>♪ 哦，我们的天父是</i>
<i>玛利亚的创造者 ♪</i>
["Happy Christmas" by Byron Lee
& the Dragonaires playing]
[拜伦·李的《圣诞快乐》</i>
[及龙之友乐队演奏中]
<i>♪ And Mary is
The mother of his Son ♪</i>
<i>♪ 而玛利亚是</i>
<i>他圣子的母亲 ♪</i>
<i>♪ The Son is a blessing
From the Father ♪</i>
<i>♪ 圣子是天父赐予的</i>
<i>祝福 ♪</i>
<i>♪ So let’s hear
Thanks and praise ♪</i>
<i>♪ 所以让我们献上</i>
<i>感谢与赞美 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Sing happy Christmas ♪</i>
<i>♪ 祝你圣诞快乐 ♪</i>
<i>♪ To you ♪</i>
<i>♪ 祝你 ♪</i>
<i>♪ You... ♪</i>
<i>♪ 你... ♪</i>
[Lindsay laughing]
Nice hat.
[林赛大笑]
帽子不错。
You look like
a Christmas supervillain.
你看起来像</i>
个圣诞超级反派。
Yeah, I am
a Christmas supervillain.
是啊，我就是</i>
一个圣诞超级反派。
You’re driving, though.
不过，你来开车。
I’m driving?
You are driving.
我开车？
你来开车。
Okay.
好吧。
Holy shit,
you got so much stuff.
我的天，
你买了这么多东西。
[laughs]
Mom’s gonna freak out.
[笑]
妈妈会吓一跳的。
Yeah, she’s gonna freak out
with joy.
是啊，她会高兴得
跳起来。
[laughs evilly]
[坏笑]
[bells jingling]
[铃铛声]
[upbeat music playing
over speakers]
[欢快的音乐播放
通过扬声器]
<i>♪ Coming back for everyone ♪</i>
<i>♪ 为每个人归来 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Christmas is
coming back again...♪</i>
<i>♪ 圣诞节
再次来临...♪</i>
Hi, Mom.
嗨，妈妈。
Okay.
好的。
[Jeffrey]
Perfect timing.
[杰弗里]
来得正好。
Everyone’s ready to go.
大家都准备好要出发了。
Mwah.
啵。
[Leigh]
Hey, guys.
[莉]
大家好。
I can’t go
to church tonight.
Why not?
我今晚不能
去教堂了。
为什么不去？
I have to wake up
super early.
我必须
起得很早。
I have a shift tomorrow.
我明天有班要上。
[Jeffrey]
Then I have good news
for you.
[杰弗里]
那我有个好消息
要告诉你。
Mitch called,
and he’s gonna be
a nice guy
米奇打电话来了，
他会
做个好人
and let you sleep in.
让你睡个懒觉。
Mitch called?
Mm-hmm. Yeah.
米奇打电话了？
嗯，是的。
Uh, said 10:30.
呃，说是10点半。
10:30?
[chuckles]
Yeah.
10点半？
[轻笑]
对。
10:30 to 4:30,
I think he said.
10点半到4点半，
他好像是这么说的。
Why? [chuckles]
怎么了？[轻笑]
I, uh... I don’t know.
我，呃...我不知道。
I mean, maybe he knows
that you have a family
我的意思是，也许他知道
你有家庭
and he wants you to be able
to spend the holidays
with them.
而且他希望你能
和他们一起
过节。
[upbeat music playing
over speakers]
[扬声器播放着
欢快的音乐]
<i>♪ Coming back
For everyone...♪</i>
<i>♪ 为了所有人...♪</i>
归来
[Lindsay chuckles]
[Leigh sniffles]
[林赛轻笑]
[Leigh抽泣]
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼。
Hey, Mom.
Hey. [chuckles]
嘿，妈妈。
嘿。[轻笑]
I love you.
[Lindsay] I love you.
我爱你。
[林赛] 我爱你。
[Leigh]
I love you.
我爱你。
[church band playing
"No Room At The Inn"]
[教堂乐队演奏
《客店无房》]
[Eileen]
<i>Come on into the manger.</i>
[艾琳]
<i>快进马厩来吧。</i>
<i>♪ Well, she said
There was no room ♪</i>
<i>♪ 她说</i>
<i>客店没有空房 ♪</i>
[choir] <i>♪ No room ♪
♪ No room ♪</i>
[合唱团] <i>♪ 没有空房 ♪</i>
<i>♪ 没有空房 ♪</i>
<i>♪ No room at the inn ♪</i>
<i>♪ 客店已满无处容身 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Well, well
The time had fully come ♪</i>
<i>♪ 唉呀</i>
<i>时机已然成熟 ♪</i>
<i>♪ For the Savior
To be born ♪</i>
<i>♪ 救世主</i>
将要诞生 ♪</i>
<i>♪ But they told her
There was no room ♪</i>
<i>♪ 但他们告诉她
没有空房 ♪</i>
<i>♪ No room ♪
♪ No room ♪</i>
<i>♪ 没有空房 ♪
♪ 没有空房 ♪</i>
<i>♪ No room at the inn ♪</i>
<i>♪ 客栈已满无处栖身 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Hey, hey, hey ♪</i>
<i>♪ 嘿 嘿 嘿 ♪</i>
<i>♪ According to the Word ♪
♪ Oh, yes ♪</i>
<i>♪ 依照圣言 ♪
♪ 哦 是的 ♪</i>
<i>♪ There was a virgin girl ♪</i>
<i>♪ 有位纯洁少女 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Hey, hey ♪
♪ Oh, yes ♪</i>
<i>♪ 嘿 嘿 ♪
♪ 哦 是的 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Mother of Jesus ♪
♪ Oh, yes ♪</i>
<i>♪ 耶稣的母亲 ♪</i>
♪ 哦 是的 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Wandering round that night ♪
♪ Oh, yes ♪</i>
<i>♪ 那夜徘徊流浪 ♪</i>
♪ 哦 是的 ♪</i>
<i>♪ She was trying
To find a place ♪</i>
<i>♪ 她正努力
寻找一处地方 ♪</i>
<i>♪ For the Savior to be born ♪</i>
<i>♪ 迎接救主降临世上 ♪</i>
<i>♪ But they told her
There was no room ♪</i>
<i>♪ 但他们告诉她
没有空房间 ♪</i>
<i>♪ No room ♪
♪ No room ♪</i>
<i>♪ 没有空房间 ♪
♪ 没有空房间 ♪</i>
<i>♪ No room at the inn ♪</i>
<i>♪ 客栈里没有空房间 ♪</i>
<i>♪ I said there was no room ♪</i>
<i>♪ 我说没有空房间 ♪</i>
<i>♪ No room ♪
♪ No room ♪</i>
<i>♪ 没有空房间 ♪
♪ 没有空房间 ♪</i>
<i>♪ No room at the inn ♪</i>
<i>♪ 客栈里没有空房间 ♪</i>
<i>♪ One more time
There was no room ♪</i>
<i>♪ 再来一次
没有空房间 ♪</i>
<i>♪ No room ♪
♪ No room ♪</i>
<i>♪ 没有空房间 ♪
♪ 没有空房间 ♪</i>
[fading]
<i>♪ No room at the inn ♪</i>
[渐弱]
<i>♪ 客栈里没有空房间 ♪</i>
<i>♪ I said the time
Had fully come ♪</i>
<i>♪ 我说时候
已经完全到了 ♪</i>
<i>♪ For the Savior
To be born...♪</i>
<i>♪ 救世主
要诞生了...♪</i>
[takes deep breath]
[深呼吸]
[grunts]
[咕哝声]
[sighs]
[叹气]
Otis, back to work. Come on.
Clean that nursery, would you?
奥蒂斯，回去干活。快点。
把育婴室打扫一下，好吗？
- Like I told you to.
- Okay.
- 就像我告诉你的那样。
- 好的。
["Sleigh Ride"
by The Ronettes playing]
["雪橇之旅"
演唱者：The Ronettes]
[panting]
[喘气]
[Mitch] <i>Hello, sir.</i>
[guard] <i>Hello.</i>
[米奇] <i>你好，先生。</i>
[警卫] <i>你好。</i>
Mr. Money Man,
Mr. Money Man.
钱先生，
钱先生。
[breathing sharply]
[急促呼吸]
<i>♪ Just hear those
Sleigh bells jingling...♪</i>
<i>♪ 听那雪橇铃铛
叮当作响...♪</i>
[Jeffrey] Good morning,
Toys "R" Us employees!
[杰弗里] 早上好，
玩具反斗城的员工们！
Hello. This is the police.
[employees screaming]
你好。我们是警察。
[员工尖叫]
You guys, you know you got
an alarm going off back there?
各位，你们知道你们那边
你们知道后面有警报在响吗？
Everybody, this way.
所有人，这边走。
You’re coming with me.
Little faster.
你跟我来。
快一点。
[employee] Oh, my God.
Oh, my God. He has a gun.
[员工] 哦，天啊。
哦，天啊。他有枪。
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
嘿，嘿，嘿，嘿，嘿！
Please keep your hand away
from your gun, sir.
请把你的手
从枪上拿开，先生。
Get on, get on your stomach.
趴下，趴在地上。
You two, come here.
你们两个，过来。
No one’s gonna get hurt if
everybody just does what I say.
如果每个人都按我说的做，
就不会有人受伤。
On your stomach. Otis, here.
趴下。奥蒂斯，这边。
Zip-tie everybody up.
把所有人都用束线带绑起来。
Otis, come on.
Uh...
奥蒂斯，快点。
呃...
Jesus Christ.
Mitch, zip-tie everybody up.
老天爷啊。
米奇，把所有人都绑起来。
Okay? Get on your stomachs,
eyes down.
明白吗？趴下，
眼睛朝下看。
[Otis] Okay.
Wh-What did I say?
[奥蒂斯] 好的。
我-我说了什么？
Come on.
On your stomach.
快点。
趴下。
Get down.
Don’t do this right now.
现在别这么做。
Hey, hey.
嘿，嘿。
What did I say?
[employees screaming, sobbing]
我说了什么？
[员工们尖叫、抽泣]
Shit.
该死。
That wasn’t my fault.
[employees whimpering]
那不是我的错。
[员工们呜咽]
He’s a bad listener.
他听不进去话。
[employees sobbing,
breathing heavily]
[员工们抽泣，
沉重地呼吸]
[Mitch]
This is not happening.
[米奇]
这不可能。
Everybody, take a breath.
大家，深呼吸。
Mitch, give me one of those.
米奇，给我一个。
Thank you, sir.
[zip ties fastening]
谢谢，先生。
[拉链绑带固定声]
[Mitch muttering]
Sorry. Sorry.
[米奇嘟囔声]
对不起。对不起。
[grunting]
Okay.
[闷哼声]
好了。
[Mitch] Sorry. Sorry.
[Jeffrey] Come on, Mitch.
[米奇] 抱歉。抱歉。
[杰弗里] 来吧，米奇。
Let’s get a hop on.
Let’s go.
我们抓紧点。
走吧。
It’s gonna be okay.
Sorry. Sorry.
会没事的。
对不起。对不起。
[groans]
[呻吟声]
Guys.
各位。
Everybody, just calm down.
I’m sorry about this.
大家先冷静下来。
对此我很抱歉。
Mitch, get the keys.
Come on.
米奇，拿钥匙。
快点。
Let’s go to the safe.
No, there’s no money here.
我们去保险柜那边。
不，这里没有钱。
There’s no safe.
You think I don’t know
没有保险箱。
你以为我不知道
that there’s a deposit that you
take to the bank every Tuesday?
你们每周二都要
存一笔存款到银行吗？
Huh? Come on, please.
嗯？拜托了，快点。
You’re okay.
你没事的。
[Mitch whimpering]
Eyes down. Eyes down.
[米奇呜咽着]
眼睛看下面。眼睛看下面。
I’m sorry about this, guys.
It’ll be all over in a second.
对此我很抱歉，各位。
马上就好了。
Come on.
You do this every day.
Calm down.
快点。
你每天都做这个的。
冷静点。
Come on. Here we go.
Good job.
来吧。开始了。
做得好。
Eyes down.
眼睛向下看。
[whimpers]
[呜咽声]
Just... find the key.
只要...找到钥匙。
Oh, God.
哦，天啊。
[Jeffrey]
Eyes down out there!
杰弗里
眼睛都看着下面！
Yes. Okay, put it in.
是的。好的，放进去。
Oh. Okay.
Put it in the safe
and open it.
哦。好的。
把它放进保险箱
然后打开。
Take the bag out.
Put it down.
把袋子拿出来。
放下。
I need you to take
the ink bomb out.
我需要你
把墨水瓶拿出来。
If I do that,
it’ll blow up everywhere.
如果我那么做，
它会炸得到处都是。
Not if you do it quick.
只要你动作快就不会。
Zip it right back up
really fast, okay?
立刻把它重新拉上
要非常快，好吗？
Okay.
好的。
Okay, good.
好的，很好。
[gasps]
[倒吸一口气]
[screaming]
[尖叫]
Oh, God.
[Mitch whimpers loudly]
哦，天啊。
[米奇大声呜咽]
Goddamn it.
该死的。
["Adeste Fideles"
by Vic Damone playing]
["Adeste Fideles"（《信徒齐来》）
维克·达蒙演唱]
[employees whimpering,
sobbing]
[员工们呜咽着，
抽泣着]
[Otis]
He needs an ambulance!
[奥蒂斯]
他需要救护车！
You said you weren’t
gonna hurt anyone,
but you hurt him!
你说过你不会
伤害任何人的，
但你伤害了他！
He needs an ambulance!
他需要救护车！
And you’re just a bully!
你就是个恶霸！
[sobbing]
You’re just a bully!
[抽泣]
你就是个恶霸！
Otis?
奥蒂斯？
<i>♪ O come, all ye faithful ♪</i>
<i>♪ 信徒齐来，快乐欢欣 ♪</i>
[crying]
I can’t see.
[哭泣]
我看不见了。
[Otis crying] He need...
he needs an ambulance.
[奥蒂斯哭泣] 他需要...
他需要救护车。
<i>♪ Joyful and triumphant... ♪</i>
<i>♪ 欢欣鼓舞... ♪</i>
I guess it’s obvious
I’m just a pushover, huh?
看来很明显
我就是个软柿子，对吧？
All right, Otis.
Fine, I’m calling 911, okay?
好了，奥蒂斯。
行，我打911，好吗？
<i>♪ To Bethlehem ♪</i>
<i>♪ 前往伯利恒 ♪</i>
[line ringing]
[电话拨号音]
<i>♪ Come and behold him ♪</i>
<i>♪ 前来瞻仰他 ♪</i>
[operator]
<i>911. What’s your emergency?</i>
[接线员]
<i>911。请问您有什么紧急情况？</i>
<i>♪ Born the king of angels ♪</i>
<i>♪ 天使之王已降生 ♪</i>
<i>♪ O come, let us ♪</i>
[Leigh gasps]
<i>♪ 来吧，让我们 ♪</i>
[莉倒吸一口气]
<i>♪ Adore him ♪</i>
Shit.
<i>♪ 敬拜他 ♪</i>
该死。
<i>♪ O come
Let us adore him ♪</i>
<i>♪ 来吧
让我们敬拜他 ♪</i>
<i>♪ O come, let us ♪</i>
Shit!
<i>♪ 来吧，让我们 ♪</i>
该死！
<i>♪ Adore him ♪</i>
<i>♪ 来崇拜他 ♪</i>
<i>♪ Christ the Lord ♪</i>
<i>♪ 主基督 ♪</i>
[alarm blaring]
[警报声大作]
[grunts in frustration]
[沮丧地咕哝]
<i>♪ Sing... ♪</i>
<i>♪ 歌唱... ♪</i>
Charlotte Police!
夏洛特警察！
Police department!
警察局！
Charlotte Police!
夏洛特警察！
<i>♪ Sing in exultation ♪</i>
<i>♪ 欢欣歌唱 ♪</i>
Oh, oh, wow. Okay.
Wait a second.
哦，哦，哇。好吧。
等一下。
<i>♪ Sing, all ye citizens... ♪</i>
<i>♪ 歌唱，所有公民... ♪</i>
You were
calling him names.
你当时在
辱骂他。
[Otis laughing]
He had a gun,
[奥蒂斯在笑]
他当时有枪，
and he was calling him
a bully.
而且他当时在骂他
是个恶霸。
[laughing]
Oh, man.
[大笑]
哦，天啊。
<i>♪ Glory to God ♪</i>
<i>♪ 荣耀归于上帝 ♪</i>
<i>♪ In the highest, glory ♪</i>
<i>♪ 至高之处，荣耀 ♪</i>
[fading] <i>♪ O come
Let us adore him...♪</i>
[渐弱] <i>♪ 来吧
让我们敬拜他...♪</i>
[officer] <i>Did you see
any part of his skin</i>
[警官] <i>你有没有看到
他身体的任何部分</i>
<i>or any other clothing?</i>
<i>或者任何其他衣物？</i>
[Leigh] <i>Um, I could tell
he was a white man, yeah.</i>
[莉] <i>嗯，我能看出
他是个白人，是的。</i>
Did you see his eyes?
你看到他的眼睛了吗？
Mm-mm.
嗯-嗯。
[Steve] This is
fucking fantastic, Jeff.
[史蒂夫] 这真是
他妈太棒了，杰夫。
You a fucking nut,
you know that?
你真是个疯子，
你知道吗？
It’s fucking great.
Baby, you see this?
这太他妈好了。
宝贝，你看到了吗？
[Michelle]
Yeah.
[米歇尔]
是的。
[Steve]
Okay, let’s see.
[史蒂夫]
好的，我们来看看。
This is your
North Carolina-issued
driver’s license, all right?
这是你的
北卡罗来纳州签发的
驾照，对吧？
That’s your passport.
Notarized birth certificate.
那是你的护照。
公证过的出生证明。
You got your check stubs
from your last job.
你有你上一份工作的
工资单存根。
Oh, and there is your ticket.
哦，还有你的机票。
You leave at 11:00 p.m.
out of Charlotte.
你晚上11点出发
从夏洛特起飞。
Now, what you’re gonna do
is a layover in Miami,
现在，你要做的是
在迈阿密转机，
and then you’re gonna fly
to Barranquilla.
然后你将飞往
巴兰基亚。
From there, you’re gonna
take a little bus
从那里，你将
乘坐一小段巴士
and it’ll have you in Venezuela
before the weekend’s out.
它就会把你送到委内瑞拉
在周末结束前就能到委内瑞拉。
Looks like I got
everything I need
看来我
需要的东西都齐了
in case I decide
to go tomorrow.
万一我决定
明天出发。
"Decide"?
"决定"？
You already made
your decision, man.
你早就
做好决定了，老兄。
What you talking about?
你什么意思？
I mean, you can’t expect me
to go on Christmas, right?
我是说，你总不能指望我
在圣诞节走吧，对吧？
Can’t I just stay awhile?
I’ll just lay low.
我就不能多待一阵子吗？
我会保持低调的。
That’s not a choice
you have, Jeff.
这可不是
你能选的，杰夫。
You got to leave tomorrow.
你明天必须走。
I got people waiting
on you, man.
我这边有人
在等你，老兄。
I got a security guy in Miami.
我在迈阿密安排了一个安保人员。
He’ll be at line three.
他会在三号登机口等你。
You got one shot, man.
11:00 p.m. tomorrow.
你只有一次机会，老兄。
明晚11点整。
Don’t miss this shot.
All right?
别错过这次机会。
明白吗？
Baby, let’s get this,
uh, wig on him.
宝贝，我们来给他
戴上假发。
[Michelle]
You bet.
[米歇尔]
当然。
One more thing
I was thinking about.
还有件事
我一直在想。
Saw on the TV
there was some shit
about a armed robbery.
电视上看到
有桩破事
关于持枪抢劫的。
I don’t know nothing
about that.
我完全不知道
这回事。
[Michelle]
I need your thumbs.
[米歇尔]
我需要你的拇指。
[sighs]
[叹气]
You know, you got
to cover your tracks, Jeff.
你知道的，你必须
掩盖你的行踪，杰夫。
- Yeah.
- Everything you touch.
- 是的。
- 你碰过的所有东西。
I need you to really think
about who you talked to,
我需要你仔细想想
你都和谁说过话，
who talked to you,
who knows your voice.
谁和你说过话，
谁认得你的声音。
I’m over a cliff for you, man.
You understand that, right?
我可是为你豁出去了，兄弟。
你明白这点，对吧？
Yeah.
明白。
So, nothing?
所以，什么都没有？
No doctor’s visits?
没去看过医生？
Uh, I went to the dentist
and got some cavities filled.
呃，我去看了牙医
补了几颗蛀牙。
But that’s it.
但就这些。
Okay. You ain’t get no X-rays?
好的。你没拍X光片吧？
No, I got X-rays,
but I gave ’em a fake name.
不，我拍了X光片，
但我用的是假名。
Okay. Well, it don’t
really matter
好吧。嗯，这其实
没什么关系
if you gave ’em a fake name
if they got your teeth, Jeff.
就算你用了假名
如果他们有你牙齿记录的话，杰夫。
[sighs] All right. Yeah.
[叹气] 好吧。是的。
Look, I’ll take care of it.
听着，我会处理好的。
Any messes you made,
you clean it up.
你搞出来的烂摊子，
你自己收拾干净。
Then you go straight
to the airport
然后你直接
去机场
and wait for your flight.
等着你的航班。
No getting on the news.
别上新闻。
No good-byes to anyone
you said hello to.
别跟任何
你打过招呼的人道别。
That means no postcards,
no calls. No none of that.
也就是说不能寄明信片，
不能打电话。这些统统不行。
["Auld Lang Syne" by Byron Lee
and the Dragonaires playing]
[拜伦·李和龙之乐队演奏的
《友谊地久天长》响起]
Shit, we had a good run.
妈的，我们风光过一阵子。
You know?
知道吗？
You know, after all this stuff
calms down and, like,
你知道，等所有这些事
平息下来，然后，
I get settled over there,
等我在那边安顿好，
do you think you could tell
some people where I’m at
你觉得你能告诉
一些人我的去向
and they maybe could...
visit me sometime?
然后他们或许可以...
偶尔来看看我？
No, no, no.
不，不，不。
It’s none of that, man.
不是这样的，老兄。
Nobody coming to see you, Jeff.
没人会来看你的，杰夫。
You’re starting over.
你要重新开始了。
You’re on your own now.
现在你只能靠自己了。
[softly] Yeah.
[轻声] 嗯。
[traffic passing]
[车辆驶过]
[liquid splashing]
[液体泼溅]
[explosion]
[爆炸声]
[glass shattering]
[玻璃破碎]
Oops.
哎呀。
[engine revving]
[引擎轰鸣]
[ringtone playing]
[铃声响起]
[Jeffrey sighs]
[杰弗里叹息]
[ringtone stops]
[铃声停止]
[ringtone playing]
[铃声响起]
[ringtone continues]
[铃声持续]
Hello?
喂？
[Leigh]
<i>John.</i>
[莉]
<i>约翰。</i>
I was just about
to call you.
我正想
给你打电话
Is everything okay?
一切都好吗？
<i>I’ve been calling you.</i>
<i>我一直在给你打电话。</i>
<i>Where are you?</i>
<i>你在哪儿？</i>
I’m driving.
我在开车
Well, actually,
I just pulled over.
其实
我刚靠边停下
<i>Are you coming
to Christmas dinner?</i>
<i>你来参加
圣诞晚餐吗？</i>
<i>The girls have been
asking for you.</i>
<i>女儿们一直
在问你。</i>
Yeah. Yeah, of course.
嗯，当然来
Yeah, I wouldn’t miss it.
我不会错过的
<i>Want to meet us at 5:00?</i>
<i>五点见面？</i>
<i>At home?</i>
<i>在家？</i>
At 5:00? Yeah, yeah,
that sounds good.
5点？好的，好的，
听起来不错。
Yeah. I’ll be there.
嗯，我会到的。
[Leigh sighs]
[莉叹气]
You there?
Are you okay?
你在听吗？
你还好吗？
I can hear you,
I can hear you breathing.
我能听见你，
我能听见你的呼吸声。
<i>I love you, John.</i>
<i>我爱你，约翰。</i>
I love you, too,
Leigh.
我也爱你，
莉。
<i>I’ll see you at 5:00.</i>
<i>那我们5点见。</i>
[line clicks, beeps]
[电话咔嗒声，哔哔声]
[airplane approaching]
[飞机接近声]
[sighs]
[叹气]
[jet engine whooshing loudly]
[喷气引擎呼啸声]
[birds chirping]
[鸟鸣声]
[engine shuts off]
[引擎熄火]
[car door closes]
[车门关闭]
[car door opens]
[车门打开]
[vehicle engine revving]
[车辆引擎加速声]
[dog barking in distance]
[远处狗叫声]
[knocking]
[敲门声]
Leigh?
Leigh？
[dog continues barking]
[狗持续吠叫]
[Jeffrey]
Merry Christmas--
圣诞快乐--
Police! Lay down!
[officers shouting]
警察！趴下！
[警员喊叫声]
Get on the ground!
Get down!
趴到地上！
蹲下！
Get on the ground!
趴到地上！
On the ground! Get down.
Get down.
趴地上！蹲下。
蹲下。
Don’t move.
别动。
Do not move.
不准动。
Doing good. Don’t move.
很好。别动。
Do as we say
and you won’t get hurt.
You understand me?
照我们说的做
你就不会受伤。
明白吗？
I got him. Nuh-uh.
我抓住他了。嗯哼。
Don’t move, dickhead.
[siren whoops]
别动，混蛋。
[警笛鸣响]
Don’t fucking move.
Drama’s over.
他妈的不准动。
闹剧结束了。
What’s your name?
你叫什么名字？
[officer over radio]
<i>What’s your name?</i>
[警官通过无线电]
<i>你叫什么名字？</i>
[Jeffrey over radio]
<i>I think you know my name.</i>
[杰弗里通过无线电]
<i>我想你知道我的名字。</i>
[officer]
<i>What’s your name?</i>
[警官]
<i>你叫什么名字？</i>
[Jeffrey]
<i>Jeffrey Manchester.</i>
[杰弗里]
<i>杰弗里·曼彻斯特。</i>
[officer] <i>PID. Target.</i>
[Scheimreif] <i>We got him.</i>
[警官] <i>PID。目标。</i>
[沙伊姆赖夫] <i>我们抓住他了。</i>
<i>We got the Roofman.</i>
<i>我们抓住屋顶男了。</i>
[indistinct
police radio chatter]
[模糊不清
无线电里警察的对话声]
[officer]
<i>He almost made it.</i>
[警官]
<i>他差点就成功了。</i>
<i>Let’s move.</i>
<i>行动。</i>
[indistinct
police radio chatter]
[模糊的
无线电通话声]
Come on.
快点。
Search his ass.
He’s a tricky motherfucker.
搜他的身。
这家伙狡猾得很。
This way. Come here.
这边。过来。
Search him good.
仔细搜。
[indistinct
police radio chatter]
[模糊的
无线电通话声]
[Jeffrey]
<i>I probably let myself
get caught.</i>
[杰弗里]
<i>也许我是故意
让自己被抓的。</i>
<i>Or maybe I just couldn’t leave
without saying goodbye.</i>
<i>又或许我只是不忍
不告而别。</i>
<i>They threw the book at me.</i>
<i>他们给我定了所有能定的罪。</i>
<i>Gave me 384 more months.</i>
<i>加判了384个月。</i>
<i>That means by the time
I get out of here,</i>
我离开这里的时候，</i>
<i>I’ll be an old man.</i>
<i>我已经是个老头了。</i>
[door closes]
[门关上]
<i>Gave me a lot of time
to think about my life.</i>
去思考我的人生。</i>
<i>Everything.</i>
<i>所有的一切。</i>
<i>When I was out there
in the world,</i>
闯荡时，</i>
<i>I wasn’t thinking
of the things</i>
那些我</i>
<i>or people that I was
putting at risk.</i>
或人。</i>
<i>Now that’s all
I think about.</i>
成了我唯一的思绪。</i>
<i>We all like to go
back in time to imagine</i>
回溯时光去想象</i>
<i>how things
could’ve gone differently</i>
可能会有怎样的不同，</i>
<i>if we made
different choices.</i>
做出不同的选择。</i>
<i>Like right now.</i>
<i>就像现在。</i>
<i>I was imagining
what it would’ve been like</i>
<i>我在想象
那会是什么样子</i>
<i>if I never committed
all those crimes</i>
<i>如果我从未犯下
那些罪行</i>
<i>and lost my family.</i>
<i>并失去我的家人。</i>
<i>Or if I got to
keep on living</i>
<i>或者如果我能
继续生活</i>
<i>with Leigh and her girls
forever.</i>
<i>和Leigh以及她的女儿们
永远在一起。</i>
<i>Sure, they’d boss me around
a little</i>
<i>当然，她们会对我呼来喝去
一点点</i>
<i>and make me go to church.</i>
<i>还会让我去教堂。</i>
<i>But they’d laugh
at my dumb jokes
and forgive me</i>
<i>但她们会笑
我那些愚蠢的笑话
并且原谅我</i>
<i>when I was on the wrong part
of cold and calculating.</i>
<i>当我处于冷酷算计的
错误一面时。</i>
<i>Or something.</i>
[honks softly]
<i>或者类似的情况。</i>
[轻声鸣喇叭]
<i>I started to realize
that all those people I loved</i>
<i>我开始意识到
所有我爱的人们</i>
<i>didn’t need me
to give them so many things.</i>
<i>并不需要我
给予他们那么多东西。</i>
<i>They just needed me.</i>
<i>他们需要的只是我这个人。</i>
<i>My time.</i>
<i>我的时间。</i>
<i>And now that’s all I have.</i>
<i>而如今我拥有的只剩这个。</i>
<i>Time.</i>
[Becky] <i>I got four A’s.</i>
<i>时间。</i>
[贝姬] <i>我得了四个A。</i>
[Jeffrey]
You got all A’s?
[杰弗里]
你全得了A？
[Becky] <i>Yeah.</i>
[贝姬] <i>是啊。</i>
Even in math? <i>Yeah.</i>
连数学也是？<i>嗯。</i>
Becky,
I’m so proud of you.
贝姬，
我真为你骄傲。
[Jeffrey]
<i>It all could’ve gone
a different way, for sure.</i>
[杰弗里]
<i>一切本有可能</i>
走向不同的结局，肯定的。</i>
<i>But it didn’t.
It went this way.</i>
<i>但事实并非如此。</i>
事情就是这样发展的。</i>
Hey, buddy.
嘿，老兄。
<i>And that was okay with me.</i>
<i>而我接受这个结果。</i>
’Cause in here, I...
因为在这里，我...
I can’t hurt anybody
anymore.
我再也伤害不了
任何人了。
Yeah. I’m...
是的。我...
I’m where I’m supposed to be.
我就在我应该在的地方。
[prisoner]
You ever think about it?
[囚犯]
你想过这事吗？
What?
什么？
[prisoner] You know,
breaking out of this place.
[囚犯] 你知道，
从这地方逃出去。
[chuckling]
[轻笑]
No. No.
Mm.
不。没有。
嗯。
I’m...
我...
This is my home now.
这里现在就是我的家了。
[prisoner 2]
You know, I have to admit,
brother, like,
[囚犯2]
你知道，我必须承认，
兄弟，就像，
that love story part
was really good.
那个爱情故事的部分
真的很棒。
I am curious.
You ever see Leigh again?
我很好奇。
你后来又见过Leigh吗？
[door buzzes]
[门嗡嗡作响]
[quiet chatter]
[轻声交谈]
[sighs]
[叹气]
[Jeffrey laughs softly]
[sighs]
[Jeffrey轻声笑]
[叹气]
[sighs]
Hey.
Hi.
嘿。
嗨。
Should I call you Jeffrey?
我该叫你Jeffrey吗？
Just another jerk Jeffrey
in your life, I guess. Yeah.
也就是你生命中的
又一个混蛋Jeffrey罢了，我想。是的。
How’s Lindsay and Dee?
Lindsay和Dee怎么样了？
They’re okay.
她们还好。
Yeah.
嗯。
Did Dee keep her bangs?
Dee还留着她的刘海吗？
She did.
她留了。
[softly]
Yeah.
[轻声地]
嗯。
[breath trembles]
[呼吸颤抖]
I’m sorry.
对不起。
[crying]
I’m so sorry that I hurt you.
[哭泣]
真的很抱歉伤害了你。
I’m sorry
I couldn’t protect you.
对不起
我没能保护你。
You don’t have anything
to be sorry about, Leigh.
你没什么
需要道歉的，莉。
You don’t.
你没有。
You didn’t hurt anybody.
你没有伤害任何人。
You just told the truth.
你只是说出了真相。
Yeah.
是啊。
I was really angry at you.
我当时真的很生你的气。
I was most angry
at how you hurt the girls.
我最生气的是
你伤害了女孩们。
[sniffles]
[抽泣]
But that’s not the way
I think about it now.
但现在我不这么
我现在是这么想的。
Okay?
好吗？
I think about it
as an adventure.
我把那看作
一次冒险。
We had a lot of fun.
[sniffles]
我们当时玩得很开心。
[抽泣]
We’re thankful.
我们很感激。
Well... [clears throat]
嗯… [清嗓子]
maybe I’ll come visit you
sometime.
也许我会找个时间
去看看你。
Gonna tap on my window?
要敲我的窗户吗？
[both chuckle]
[两人轻笑]
Maybe I’ll just knock
on the door. [laughs]
也许我会直接敲
门。[笑]
[sniffles]
[抽泣]
[crying softly]
[轻声哭泣]
[reporter] <i>The Roofman
has returned to rob again,</i>
[记者] <i>“飞贼”
再次归来作案，</i>
<i>overnight cutting his way
into this McDonald’s</i>
<i>昨夜他破顶而入，
潜入这家位于
<i>on the intersection
of Wilkinson and Main.</i>
交叉路口的这家麦当劳。</i>
[man] Just to look
at what he’s done,
it appears
he’s very intelligent.
Um, it’s just that
he also likes to commit crime.
[reporter 2]
<i>Holes cut into the roofs,</i>
[记者2]
<i>屋顶被凿穿了洞</i>
<i>workers told
to get into the coolers,</i>
<i>员工们被命令</i>
<i>进入冷藏库</i>
<i>but no one was hurt.</i>
<i>但无人受伤。</i>
<i>In fact,
the suspect was nice.</i>
<i>实际上</i>
<i>这名嫌疑人还挺友善。</i>
[man 2]
Very polite person.
[男子2]
He always makes sure
that the employees,
before he walked them
into the refrigerator,
进入冷藏室，
that he has them
put on their coats
他让员工们
穿上外套
so that they’ll stay warm.
以免着凉。
[reporter 3]
<i>This was an earlier
composite drawing of Roofman,</i>
[记者3]
<i>这是早些时候
“屋顶人”的模拟画像，</i>
<i>always wearing a mask.</i>
<i>他总是戴着面具。</i>
<i>The owner here
refused to comment</i>
<i>这里的店主
拒绝就抢劫案的</i>
<i>on all details
of the robbery,</i>
<i>所有细节
发表评论，</i>
<i>referring calls to
the McDonald’s corporation.</i>
<i>将所有问询
转至麦当劳公司。</i>
<i>But he’s also robbed
Burger King and Blockbuster...</i>
<i>但他还抢劫过
汉堡王和百视达...</i>
[reporter 4] <i>Police caught him
with $9,000 in cash,</i>
[记者4] <i>警方抓获他时
他身上有9000美元现金，</i>
<i>allegedly stolen from
two McDonald’s restaurants,</i>
<i>据称是从
两家麦当劳餐厅偷来的，</i>
<i>the first in Gastonia,
the second in Belmont.</i>
<i>第一次发生在加斯托尼亚，
第二次在贝尔蒙特。</i>
<i>The suspect
almost got away,</i>
<i>嫌疑人
差点逃脱，</i>
<i>until a worker
at this Belmont McDonald’s</i>
<i>直到一名
贝尔蒙特麦当劳的员工</i>
<i>saw which way he ran
and then called police.</i>
<i>看清他逃跑的方向
随后报警。</i>
I interacted with Jeffrey
on the robbery that happened
in the McDonald’s in Belmont.
我就贝尔蒙特麦当劳抢劫案
与杰弗里有过接触
。</i>
<i>The whole time,
he was saying,</i>
<i>整个过程中，
他一直在说，</i>
<i>"I’m so sorry. You guys
are the good people.</i>
<i>"非常抱歉。你们
都是好人。</i>
<i>I’m the bad person."</i>
<i>我才是坏人。"</i>
He was a nice fella.
他是个不错的家伙。
He, uh, he was real nice.
他，呃，他真的很友善。
He didn’t, uh...
he didn’t come across as, uh...
他没有，呃...
他没有表现得，呃...
you know, come up,
talk junk, you know.
你知道的，走上前来，
说些废话，你懂的。
Or, "Why am I here?"
Nothing like that.
或者，“我为什么在这儿？”
完全没有那种情况。
You know, he...
he was a nice fella.
你知道，他……
他是个不错的家伙。
He’s an incredible liar,
他是个厉害的骗子，
um, pretty much
about everything.
嗯，几乎是
在所有事情上。
Everybody thinks,
"Oh, he’s such a hero
大家都以为，
“哦，他真是个英雄
"because he-he gave the toys
to the children."
因为他把玩具
送给了孩子们。”
Well, the toys are stolen.
但那些玩具是偷来的。
[Pastor Ron Smith] As far as,
like, having an inkling
[罗恩·史密斯牧师] 至于说，
像是，有过一丝
to maybe
there’s something there,
可能
觉得有什么不对劲，
no, I didn’t have
any kind of inkling.
不，我没有任何
那种预感。
He was a nice fella.
He got involved in our church.
他是个好人。
他加入了我们的教会。
[reporter 5]
<i>But now that the pastor knows</i>
[记者5]
<i>但现在牧师既然知道</i>
<i>John is really
Jeffrey Manchester,</i>
<i>约翰实际上是</i>
杰弗里·曼彻斯特，</i>
<i>the escaped convict accused
of sticking up Toys "R" Us</i>
<i>那个被指控抢劫玩具反斗城</i>
并纵火烧毁</i>
<i>and torching
a dentist’s office,
how does he feel?</i>
<i>牙医诊所的</i>
越狱逃犯，</i>
他作何感想？</i>
My belief is that, um,
我的信念是，嗯，
as a church,
you got to stand with somebody.
作为一个教会，
你必须支持某个人。
Doesn’t mean that you agree
with what they did.
这并不意味着你赞同
他们的所作所为。
The Roofman,
or the Rooftop Robber,
那个“屋顶大盗”，
或者叫“天台劫匪”，
I-I never heard
anything about that.
我-我从未听说过
任何关于那件事的消息。
It was--
I was oblivious to anything
那是——
我之前对一切都毫无察觉
until after my relationship
with Jeffrey,
直到我和杰弗里的关系
结束之后，
and then he was captured.
然后他就被捕了。
Then it just seemed
to be everywhere.
之后这件事似乎
就变得人尽皆知了。
[scoffs] Never thought that
would happen to my office,
[嗤笑] 我从没想过
这种事会发生在我的办公室，
him trying to burn it down
to-to hide his record.
他试图放火烧掉它
来——来掩盖他的记录。
The whole front area was gone.
整个前厅区域都被毁了。
In the beginning,
it just seemed to me
一开始，
在我看来
he had everything together.
他似乎一切都很完美。
And it’s a perfect example
of how greed and money
这是一个绝佳的例子
说明了贪婪、金钱
and bad influences in your life
could change your outcome.
以及生活中的不良影响
是如何改变一个人的结局的。
[reporter 5]
<i>Pastor Smith says</i>
[记者5]
<i>史密斯牧师说</i>
<i>he’s already visited
Manchester in jail.</i>
<i>他已经去监狱</i>
探望过曼彻斯特。</i>
He could not believe
that I came to see him,
他不敢相信
我会去看望他，
that, um, that we would
not just be really mad at him
不敢相信，嗯，我们
没有只是对他大发雷霆
and turn our back on him.
并对他置之不理。</i>
[reporter 5]
<i>Although it was
a church member</i>
[记者5]
<i>尽管正是</i>
<i>一位教会成员</i>
<i>who turned Manchester in.</i>
<i>举报了曼彻斯特。</i>
<i>Police captured him</i>
<i>警方是在</i>
<i>leaving the apartment
of Leigh Wainscott,</i>
<i>他离开利·温斯柯特的</i>
<i>公寓时抓获他的，</i>
<i>the new girlfriend he met
at a church singles event.</i>
<i>这位新女友是他在</i>
<i>教会单身活动中认识的。</i>
I talked to my oldest daughter,
you know, about this,
我和我的大女儿谈过，
你知道，关于这件事，
um, recently,
and, uh, I asked her
嗯，最近，
然后，呃，我让她
to share with me
anything that she remembered,
跟我分享
她记得的任何事情，
um, that she could share,
and she just said,
呃，她能分享的，
她只是说，
"Oh, yeah,
I remember very well.
"哦，是的，
我记得很清楚。
"He was, he was awesome,
you know.
"他，他真的很棒，
你知道的。
"We had so much fun."
"我们玩得非常开心。"
And, um...
然后，呃...
They didn’t have anything bad
to say about him.
她们没有任何不好的话
要说他。
Nothing at all.
一点都没有。
[music ends]
[音乐结束]